<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Msgs Tag on Nathan&#39;s Site</title>
	<link>https://nthp.me/msg/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Msgs on Nathan&#39;s Site</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-us</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 21:40:57 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nthp.me/msg/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss" />
	<item>
	  <title>Master Ski Game</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/msg/msg/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 21:40:57 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/msg/msg/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;center&gt;	
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rules&#34;&gt;Rules&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Object of the Game - The object of the game is to collect as few Points of Shame (see section 3) as possible. The contestant who collects the most Points of Shame at the end of a ski season earns the title of POS (Piece of Shit/Prince of Shame) for that season. After 10 years of play, the total number of seasonal POS are added together, and the player with the most seasonal POS becomes the POS of the Decade&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contestants - A contestant is only eligible to participate in the Master Ski Game if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i. The potential participant is a skier. As it is the Master Ski Game, skiboarders, sledders, and
snowboarder filth are not eligible for participation. Furthermore, skiblades are eligible, but
highly frowned upon, and should be avoided if possible. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ii. The potential participant has been skiing before. As it is the Master Ski Game, complete
beginners are not eligible. It is to be noted that, while a contestant is eligible after his first
skiing trip, it is suggested that a potential participant complete his first skiing season before
participating. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iii. The potential participant must be physically able to ski during the majority of the ski season. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Falling - Falling is defined as a point where a contestant comes to a complete or almost complete stop with either a hip, shoulder, buttock, or combination thereof in contact with the slope. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points of Shame - Points of Shame (henceforth “PsOS”) are how the Master Ski Game is scored. As in golf, points are not desirable. A contestant may earn PsOS for the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i. The contestant will receive two PsOS per fall* on a Green Circle slope. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ii. The contestant will receive one Point of Shame per fall* on either a Blue Square or a Black Diamond slope. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iii. The contestant will receive two PsOS per fall* on a Double Black Diamond slope. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iv. The contestant will receive five PsOS if he falls while entering or exiting the chairlift. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v. Falling in a terrain park (of any difficulty level) rewards no PsOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disqualification - If at any point in time a contestant leaves the resort before the rest of their party, or before their ticket has expired. Exceptions include but are limited to, family emergencies, and party approved exceptions*.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a single contestant earns all 10 seasonal POS titles, he becomes the POS for Life (Dumb Fuck).&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>