<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Nathan&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>https://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Nathan&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Msg</title>
      <link>https://example.org/msg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 21:40:57 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/msg/</guid>
      <description>Rules The Object of the Game - The object of the game is to collect as few Points of Shame (see section 3) as possible. The contestant who collects the most Points of Shame at the end of a ski season earns the title of POS (Piece of Shit/Prince of Shame) for that season. After 10 years of play, the total number of seasonal POS are added together, and the player with the most seasonal POS becomes the POS of the Decade1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>States</title>
      <link>https://example.org/states/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 20:22:06 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/states/</guid>
      <description> ![](_pics/fig1.png) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extras</title>
      <link>https://example.org/extras/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 17:55:06 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/extras/</guid>
      <description>States I&amp;rsquo;ve Been To A map of states that I have been to, and did something in (i.e. Something other than drive straight though, or changing planes)
Factorio Blueprints A list of some of my Factorio blueprints, including import strings
Geocaching Files A couple of downloadable log files for Geocaching</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Feeds</title>
      <link>https://example.org/my-feeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 17:52:56 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/my-feeds/</guid>
      <description>Jump to: Podcasts | Blogs
Podcasts 🔗 Active / Simi-Active 🔗 Lehto&amp;rsquo;s Law Posts: 1 - 3x per day Length: ~10min
Steve Lehto: author, attorney. Over 30 years of practicing Michigan Lemon Law and more than a dozen books written.
Apple Podcasts | Overcast | PocketCasts | Youtube
Techlinked Posts: Every Mon, Wed, Thu Length: ~10min
A thrice-weekly news show about tech + gaming culture
Apple Podcasts | Overcast | PocketCasts | Youtube</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things I Use</title>
      <link>https://example.org/things-i-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 17:49:19 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/things-i-use/</guid>
      <description>Things I Use Jump to: Hardware | Home Servers | Software | Web Tools | Disclaimer
For a list of podcasts and blogs I like, go here.
Hardware 🔗 Phone: iPhone 14 Pro in Space Black w/ 256GB Storage
Tablet: 6th gen iPad mini
Watch: Apple Watch Ultra
Laptop: Late 2020 M1 MacBook Pro w/ 16GB Ram and 512GB Storage in Space Gray
Monitor: LG UltraWide 35WN75C
Keyboard: WASD VP3 w/ MX Blues1</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://example.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 17:38:57 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me I&amp;rsquo;m Nathan, I&amp;rsquo;m a computer nerd who loves to travel, and do many other things.
This is my blog. I mostly use this place as a place to post longer form content. Mostly of me rambling off about something. Posts here will mostly be about things I’m interested in, or whatever is on my mind.
If for some terrifying reason you like this crap, you can subscribe via RSS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stealth Flipper</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/stealth-flipper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 12:30:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/stealth-flipper/</guid>
      <description>Being More Stealthy With A Flipper Let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, most flipper users use the flipper to dick around. You know, pop Tesla charge covers, set off CVS alcohol announcements (Bonus points if you do it in a state CVS can&amp;rsquo;t sell alcohol in (Like Maryland)). You know, fun stuff. The Flipper is unfortunately recognizable (Thanks to dumpsters like TikTok). So, if we&amp;rsquo;re going to have some fun in a CVS, or a Tesla store, we need to be a bit sneaky.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PaintBoy Advance</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/paintboy-advance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 12:10:57 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/paintboy-advance/</guid>
      <description>PaintBoy advance I&amp;rsquo;m not new to modded gameboys. I&amp;rsquo;ve put IPS screens in a DMG and an SP, and I built an all metal gameboy advance. Ive gotten the itch to build a custom GBA again after working on my girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s GBA, I just need an idea…
This is what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking. This is made from painting the inside of a clear shell, allowing the supports to still be seen. This isn&amp;rsquo;t mine it&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot from this YouTube vid.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
