<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Steam Deck Tag on Nathan&#39;s Site</title>
	<link>https://nthp.me/tags/steam-deck/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Steam Deck on Nathan&#39;s Site</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-us</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 11:21:40 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nthp.me/tags/steam-deck/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss" />
	<item>
	  <title>Deck OLED</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/deck-oled/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 11:21:40 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/deck-oled/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Dec 4, 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little while back, I upgraded my Deck. No, not the wooden thing on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.pinimg.com/originals/39/10/c1/3910c1cfeca4d66d3d1d403ee74940bf.gif&#34;&gt;back of a house&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about the Steam Deck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a Steam Deck for a little over a year. And over that year, the deck has gone from really cool, but needs to work. To&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Om8iSXUAKh0&#34;&gt;well&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt; Needless to say, I really like the Deck, and even upgraded mine to 2TB of storage. So when Valve announced the Deck OLED, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it looked cool as hell. And would love to have one. My first thought, was simply to build an upgrade kit from parts. Pick up a new shell, and the OLED panel (once it hit iFixit), and boom, kinda Deck OLED&amp;hellip; Valve said no. The parts are not inter-compatible. So I bought one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I caved. And I don&amp;rsquo;t regret it. The main big upgrade (being the OLED screen), is fantastic. But, there are a number of other smaller upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Deck LCD&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Deck OLED&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Screen Size&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&amp;quot;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.4&amp;quot;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Screen Refresh&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60Hz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90Hz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Battery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;40Whr&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50Whr&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CPU Node&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6nm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7nm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Weight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1lb 7.6oz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1lb 6.6oz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cup Holder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radioisotope_thermoelectric_generator&#34;&gt;RTG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;😰&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;☢️&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, not really on that last one&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most noticeable improvements, is the build quality. The Deck LCD wasn&amp;rsquo;t built poorly, but the OLED is just more sturdy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shrunk down APU, combined with the OLED screen, and the bigger battery, do wonders for battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could go on for a bit on all of the little changes, but channels like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0pBQ4dosuT0&amp;amp;pp=ygUNbHR0IGRlY2sgb2xlZA%3D%3D&#34;&gt;LTT&lt;/a&gt;, already &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uCVXqoVi6RE&amp;amp;pp=ygUNbHR0IGRlY2sgb2xlZA%3D%3D&#34;&gt;have&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1tb-is-not-enough&#34;&gt;1TB Is Not Enough&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1TB is plenty for a handheld, but I had a 2TB SSD, and I wanted to move it over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with cracking my LCD open, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/R0S8JZ6YO5c?si=Kv9rVkjzSWNLzfRY&amp;amp;t=23&#34;&gt;extracting&lt;/a&gt; the 2TB SSD. After making sure all my non cloud synced stuff was backed up, I gave it a quick format. I then moved to the OLED. Cracking that open was much nicer. The OLED uses Torx screws, vs Philips. This is great, as Torx screws don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cam_out&#34;&gt;cam out&lt;/a&gt;. With the blank 2TB SSD in the OLED, and the old 1TB SSD in an external enclosure. I was ready. I popped a clonezilla boot disk into the SD card slot, and fired it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clonezilla on the Deck is super easy to use. You can set up the whole operation with just the D-pad, and the A button&amp;hellip; You just can&amp;rsquo;t start the clone. Clonezilla is really adamant that you press &lt;kbd&gt;Y&lt;/kbd&gt; to start the clone&amp;hellip; So you need to plug in a keyboard, to press one key&amp;hellip; Great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 40 minutes into the clone. I decided to move the deck to a more powerful power adapter&amp;hellip; The moment I unplugged the cable, my docking adapter, blinked&amp;hellip; Causing clonezilla to shit itself, as the source SSD dropped off&amp;hellip; Now I had to start over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the second clone attempt was done, I fired up the Deck. After waiting for SteamOS to auto expand the partition, it was done. A 2TB handheld, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jpDL2l-MWEU&#34;&gt;in the palm of my hand&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Deck OLED is a fantastic upgrade, and I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with mine. The 90Hz screen is fantastic for Halo. And the HDR OLED, makes everything pop in ways the old Deck just couldn&amp;rsquo;t. The Deck OLED is more than just a screen upgrade. And that, is what got me to pick one up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.13a8f@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Deck%20OLED&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📨&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.13a8f@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.13a8f@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Deck OLED&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>