<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Old Game Systems Tag on Nathan&#39;s Site</title>
	<link>https://nthp.me/tags/old-game-systems/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Old Game Systems on Nathan&#39;s Site</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-us</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 17:17:57 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nthp.me/tags/old-game-systems/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss" />
	<item>
	  <title>My New Old Webcam</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/my-new-old-webcam/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 17:17:57 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/my-new-old-webcam/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Nov 13, 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had an Analogue Pocket for a while now. If you don&amp;rsquo;t known what the Pocket is, it’s a handheld FPGA game system. Capable of replicating a ton of old game systems. You can learn more about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.analogue.co/pocket&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. One neat thing about the Pocket, it has a GB / GBA slot on it. I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing GBA games on it since I got it. But only recently, did I pick up its dock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dock, let&amp;rsquo;s you plug it into a TV. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Alright, it also has two USB ports on it, and let&amp;rsquo;s you connect a bunch of different wireless controllers. After using the dock for a few days, I had an idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite a while back. People were sharing an article about how a dude used a GameBoy Camera for Zoom. There was nothing really special about it. He was using a Pocket, its dock, and a cheap capture card. So I bought a cheap capture card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;https://nthp.me/pics/My-New-Old-Webcam/fig1.jpeg&#34;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Taken using macOS Photo Booth&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a little concerned about the adaptor. It was shocking light. To the point I didn&amp;rsquo;t think It was going to work. But somewhat to my surprise, it did, and it looked pretty good. I work two jobs. One in loss prevention, and the other as a cybersecurity TA. The latter of the two is a remote job. And perfect for this type of thing. I&amp;rsquo;m defiantly looking forward to using it there, when I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.13a8f@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20My%20New%20Old%20Webcam&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📫&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.13a8f@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.13a8f@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: My New Old Webcam&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>PaintBoy Advance</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/paintboy-advance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 12:10:57 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/paintboy-advance/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Oct 26, 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;paintboy-advance&#34;&gt;PaintBoy advance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not new to modded gameboys. I&amp;rsquo;ve put IPS screens in a DMG and an SP, and I built an &lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@Sulairris/106783968641330983&#34;&gt;all metal gameboy advance&lt;/a&gt;. Ive gotten the itch to build a custom GBA again after working on my girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s GBA, I just need an idea…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nthp.me/pics/paintboy/fig1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking. This is made from painting the inside of a clear shell, allowing the supports to still be seen. This isn&amp;rsquo;t mine it&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot from &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/XF_DDf9N1hc&#34;&gt;this YouTube vid&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to build the full thing yet, just see if I can make the shell myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ordered a clear replacement shell that&amp;rsquo;s been pre-modded to take an IPS display, just need to buy some spray paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many days later thanks to USPS, the shell came in the mail. It&amp;rsquo;s a clear retrosix shell and its one of the better ones I&amp;rsquo;ve seen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nthp.me/pics/paintboy/fig2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I needed was some spray paint, so I grabbed my super gameboy, jumped in my car and headed up to the home depot. After looking over the spray paint aisle, they didn&amp;rsquo;t really have what I was looking for, but I got something close. Oddly, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Btv1OD_CUAAICrF?format=jpg&amp;amp;name=medium&#34;&gt;my home state&lt;/a&gt; Maryalnd requires you to be at least 18 to buy spray paint. Good thing i&amp;rsquo;m 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really my first time spray painting anything, but I have watched some modding vids that go over it. After taping up the outside, cracking the garage door, I got to work. I put down one layer, then another, then another, and waited. After peeling the tape off, it came out pretty good. Some over spray on the edges, but for a first time ensnarement, it went pretty well. I&amp;rsquo;ll build something in this down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.13a8f@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20PaintBoy%20Advance&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.13a8f@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.13a8f@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: PaintBoy Advance&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nthp.me/pics/paintboy/fig3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nthp.me/pics/paintboy/fig4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>