<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Cars Tag on Nathan&#39;s Site</title>
	<link>https://nthp.me/tags/cars/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Cars on Nathan&#39;s Site</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-us</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 14:29:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nthp.me/tags/cars/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss" />
	<item>
	  <title>Self Service Test Drive - Test drive a car, you found at a mall</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/self-service-test-drive/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 14:29:06 -0400</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/self-service-test-drive/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Last week, my coworker was telling how he was going to test drive a Tesla. &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s cool&amp;rdquo;, I thought. Then he told me it was a self service test drive. Wait, what‽ I need to check this out. So, I signed up for one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Signing up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sign up was pretty simple. I just went to Tesla&amp;rsquo;s website, and picked the car I wanted to test drive. After picking the Model 3, I put in my zip, picked the local mall from the available locations, and picked a time slot, Monday at 3PM. The rest, was done in the Tesla app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After logging in, it had me upload my license&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and watch some videos. I did have to do a phone interview. It was just a quick, &amp;ldquo;what make&amp;rsquo;s you interested in a Tesla&amp;rdquo; type thing. They did confirm some info, and gave me some basic rules. Only I could drive, and don&amp;rsquo;t leave it at the charger when I&amp;rsquo;m done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Monday rolled around, I headed up to the mall. And there it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webp&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The car&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig2.webp&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The app letting make the car fart. Yes, I did hit it&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went up to the car, right when 3 o&amp;rsquo;clock hit. My phone connected to it, and the door unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Drive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting in, my first impression was just how much I could see. The big windshield, and lack of center instrument panel really allows for a great view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figre&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig4.webp&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A big view&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might notice, that a lot is missing here&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. No stalks at all, or climate consoles, or a shifter, and those missing instruments, what‽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, nothing is really missing, they&amp;rsquo;ve just moved. The turn signals and wipers are buttons on the wheel. Shifting and climate are on the touch screen. And so are the instruments. How long did that take me to get used to? About ten minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking, climate, on the touch screen‽ That sounds horrible! But, it really isn&amp;rsquo;t that bad. Air flow presences get set to your driver profile, so just set it, and forget it. As for changing the temperature, just use the really good voice control. And let the automatic climate control do its thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for driving the thing, it did take a while to get used to one peddle driving.  Having the car start essentially braking when I let off the accelerator was weird. I did make the decision to drive for a bit in the empty parking lot, to get used to things. I also used that space to play with the self parking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Letting the car operate itself was weird. It went against everything that I was taught. It just felt wrong, but it was just so cool. I did try the self driving a little&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the biggest fan of the roads out here. I did love how it would beep when the light turned green. It did it right when it went green when I was at the front of the line, and when the car in front of me started moving, when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, my test drive was over pretty quick. I only had an hour to drive the car. So I parked it where they wanted, locked it, and left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig3.webp&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This specific car was the duel motor 2024 Model 3. And man, was it nice. From the crazy takeoff power, the comfort, and features every new car should have (beeping at you to let you known that the light is green, and blind spot cameras), it was way cooler than I expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not cheep though. This trim starts at $47,740. While I&amp;rsquo;m not in the market for a new car&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m defiantly going to keep the Model 3 in the back of my mind, for when I eventually am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the whole self service demo thing. I loved it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t truly have to BS a sales rep to do a test drive. And I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to talk with anyone in the car. That part, was fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Self%20Serve%20Test%20Drive&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📪&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Self Serve Test Drive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard practice for any test drive.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re used to a normal car, like I am.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t have the full self driving package. Just the auto speed, and auto steer.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And probably won&amp;rsquo;t be for quite a while.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Oil Time - Knock knock, it&#39;s the U.S.</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/oil/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 20:41:11 -0400</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/oil/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;The time has come, time to take the oil out of my car, wash it, and toss it back in&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webp&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;On the jack stand&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never liked getting under my car. I don&amp;rsquo;t have an issue with getting under cars, just mine. She&amp;rsquo;s a low car, so I have to jack it up a fair big to squeeze myself under it, That&amp;rsquo;s the part I don&amp;rsquo;t like&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Removing of the oil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting under the car, and getting the drain plug out, she was pissing oil out. That part was easy, after remembering what size socket I needed. Getting the filter off, was a different story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving over to the oil filter, I put my filter wrench on. And it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t fully grab. No big deal, I&amp;rsquo;ve had that before. After about ten minutes of banging the filter adapter on, it sill wouldn&amp;rsquo;t grab&amp;hellip; After getting out from under the car, I looked in the tool box, and realized something. The filter adapter I was trying to use, wasn&amp;rsquo;t for my car. It was was for my old Civic. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grabbing the right adapter, the filter came off real easy. Using the right tools really helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting the new filter on&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, it was time for my favorite part under the car. Being done under the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adding of the oil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the car off of the jack stand. I dumped some oil in. After putting most of the oil in, I went to start the car for a few seconds&amp;hellip; It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t start. Turns out, the key fob needs to be in the car. You know, where it has to be for the computer to start the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rest of the oil in, and the dip stick happy, I was done. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t mind doing my own oil, it&amp;rsquo;s cheeper, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t take long. But man, I don&amp;rsquo;t like working on low cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone wondering what car I drive, she&amp;rsquo;s a 2015 Honda Accord EX-L, with a 2.4L i-VTECH DOHC mated to a CVT. Super fun to drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Oil%20Time&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📨&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Oil Time&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m joking, calm down.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I do rest the frame onto a jack stand, as you can see in the photo.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I put a touch of oil around the seal.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>