<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Nathan&#39;s Site</title>
	<link>https://nthp.me/posts/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Posts on Nathan&#39;s Site</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-us</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 08:30:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nthp.me/posts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss" />
	<item>
	  <title>Self Service Test Drive - Test drive a car, you found at a mall</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/self-service-test-drive/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 14:29:06 -0400</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/self-service-test-drive/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Last week, my coworker was telling how he was going to test drive a Tesla. &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s cool&amp;rdquo;, I thought. Then he told me it was a self service test drive. Wait, what‽ I need to check this out. So, I signed up for one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Signing up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sign up was pretty simple. I just went to Tesla&amp;rsquo;s website, and picked the car I wanted to test drive. After picking the Model 3, I put in my zip, picked the local mall from the available locations, and picked a time slot, Monday at 3PM. The rest, was done in the Tesla app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After logging in, it had me upload my license&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and watch some videos. I did have to do a phone interview. It was just a quick, &amp;ldquo;what make&amp;rsquo;s you interested in a Tesla&amp;rdquo; type thing. They did confirm some info, and gave me some basic rules. Only I could drive, and don&amp;rsquo;t leave it at the charger when I&amp;rsquo;m done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Monday rolled around, I headed up to the mall. And there it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webp&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The car&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig2.webp&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The app letting make the car fart. Yes, I did hit it&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went up to the car, right when 3 o&amp;rsquo;clock hit. My phone connected to it, and the door unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Drive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting in, my first impression was just how much I could see. The big windshield, and lack of center instrument panel really allows for a great view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figre&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig4.webp&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A big view&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might notice, that a lot is missing here&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. No stalks at all, or climate consoles, or a shifter, and those missing instruments, what‽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, nothing is really missing, they&amp;rsquo;ve just moved. The turn signals and wipers are buttons on the wheel. Shifting and climate are on the touch screen. And so are the instruments. How long did that take me to get used to? About ten minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking, climate, on the touch screen‽ That sounds horrible! But, it really isn&amp;rsquo;t that bad. Air flow presences get set to your driver profile, so just set it, and forget it. As for changing the temperature, just use the really good voice control. And let the automatic climate control do its thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for driving the thing, it did take a while to get used to one peddle driving.  Having the car start essentially braking when I let off the accelerator was weird. I did make the decision to drive for a bit in the empty parking lot, to get used to things. I also used that space to play with the self parking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Letting the car operate itself was weird. It went against everything that I was taught. It just felt wrong, but it was just so cool. I did try the self driving a little&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the biggest fan of the roads out here. I did love how it would beep when the light turned green. It did it right when it went green when I was at the front of the line, and when the car in front of me started moving, when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, my test drive was over pretty quick. I only had an hour to drive the car. So I parked it where they wanted, locked it, and left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig3.webp&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This specific car was the duel motor 2024 Model 3. And man, was it nice. From the crazy takeoff power, the comfort, and features every new car should have (beeping at you to let you known that the light is green, and blind spot cameras), it was way cooler than I expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not cheep though. This trim starts at $47,740. While I&amp;rsquo;m not in the market for a new car&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m defiantly going to keep the Model 3 in the back of my mind, for when I eventually am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the whole self service demo thing. I loved it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t truly have to BS a sales rep to do a test drive. And I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to talk with anyone in the car. That part, was fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Self%20Serve%20Test%20Drive&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📪&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Self Serve Test Drive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard practice for any test drive.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re used to a normal car, like I am.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t have the full self driving package. Just the auto speed, and auto steer.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And probably won&amp;rsquo;t be for quite a while.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Loosing What You Bought - Was it yours to start with?</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/loosing-what-you-bought/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:34:08 -0400</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/loosing-what-you-bought/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Earlier today, I was watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QZYy9KzFT2w&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;. In it, Shelby goes over a number of games that can&amp;rsquo;t be played anymore. Physical PC games, that you can install (even on period hardware), but can&amp;rsquo;t launch. Why? Because Windows Live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, not just Windows Live, but all online activation systems. The issue is, a lot of old games, have had their activation servers shut down. So that physical copy of Red Faction Guerrilla you might have ( / own), can&amp;rsquo;t run. Because it can&amp;rsquo;t talk to a dead server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shelby also goes on for a bit about Steam. Manly, how Steam no longer runs on Windows XP. The issue he cites here, is that a physical copy of Half-Life 2, won&amp;rsquo;t work on an XP computer now. However, I see Steam as a middle ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Middle Ground&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steam, while it won&amp;rsquo;t run on Windows XP anymore&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. You still have the game, and can still play it, just on newer hardware. Its part of you &amp;ldquo;forever library&amp;rdquo;. That is, so long as the game doesn&amp;rsquo;t have extra DRM built in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I really don&amp;rsquo;t like, is when publishers shoehorn in extra DRM/launchers into their Steam games. I can&amp;rsquo;t play The Sims 4 on an airplane&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, not because the game itself needs the internet, but because the EA App launcher, needs to do an online check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webp&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;My Deck OLED in Airplane mode&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steam has shown, over the years, to be more trustworthy, than the other options. I trust Steam, I don&amp;rsquo;t trust EA, or Ubisoft, or the others. Vale has shown, that Steam is in it for the long haul. Having to upgrade every now and then to still use it, is a compromise I&amp;rsquo;m fine with making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not dreading, when Steam dies, I&amp;rsquo;m dreading, when He dies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lord Gaben&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig2.webp&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Lord Gaben&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gabe Newell, the man in charge in Vale/Steam. Gabe has done a lot for PC gaming, being less a man of voice, and more a man of action. Steam helped break people free from a lot of DRM crap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to stop piracy is not by putting anti-piracy technology to work. It’s by giving those people a service that’s better than what they’re receiving from the pirates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;- Gabe Newell&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, games are going back in that direction. Needing to sign in to an extra launcher on every launch, having to hand shake with a server, etc. Multiplayer games are one thing, but this is hitting single player games hard. And it as been, for too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steam can handle pretty much all of this, and in a way that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make people angry. But publisher choose, not to use those systems. They are choosing, to use solutions that won&amp;rsquo;t last, that hurt the consumer both now, and down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t fear the death of steam. I fear the death of the man at the helm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Loosing%20What%20You%20Bought&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📪&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Loosing What You Bought&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some old games might not like that, but Windows compatibility settings / running the game through Proton on Linux/SteamDeck should fix that.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without paying for internet access.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>To Things From RSS Test Post - Checked luggage costs extra</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/to-things-from-rss-test-post/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 18:10:59 -0400</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/to-things-from-rss-test-post/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking around for a while for a good RSS to [thing] poster. Something that looks at an RSS feed, and when it see a new item, makes a post. I know you can do that with IFTTT, but IFTTT doesn&amp;rsquo;t support Mastodon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a few out there, but none of the liked my RSS feed&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Well, a new one popped up, and didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have a problem when I added my feed. This post is going to serve as a test of &lt;a href=&#34;https://echofeed.app&#34;&gt;EchoFeed&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll post an update if it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: It worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webp&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20To%20Things%20From%20RSS&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: To Things From RSS&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they were the only thing that didn&amp;rsquo;t like it.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Oil Time - Knock knock, it&#39;s the U.S.</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/oil/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 20:41:11 -0400</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/oil/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;The time has come, time to take the oil out of my car, wash it, and toss it back in&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webp&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;On the jack stand&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never liked getting under my car. I don&amp;rsquo;t have an issue with getting under cars, just mine. She&amp;rsquo;s a low car, so I have to jack it up a fair big to squeeze myself under it, That&amp;rsquo;s the part I don&amp;rsquo;t like&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Removing of the oil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting under the car, and getting the drain plug out, she was pissing oil out. That part was easy, after remembering what size socket I needed. Getting the filter off, was a different story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving over to the oil filter, I put my filter wrench on. And it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t fully grab. No big deal, I&amp;rsquo;ve had that before. After about ten minutes of banging the filter adapter on, it sill wouldn&amp;rsquo;t grab&amp;hellip; After getting out from under the car, I looked in the tool box, and realized something. The filter adapter I was trying to use, wasn&amp;rsquo;t for my car. It was was for my old Civic. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grabbing the right adapter, the filter came off real easy. Using the right tools really helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting the new filter on&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, it was time for my favorite part under the car. Being done under the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adding of the oil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the car off of the jack stand. I dumped some oil in. After putting most of the oil in, I went to start the car for a few seconds&amp;hellip; It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t start. Turns out, the key fob needs to be in the car. You know, where it has to be for the computer to start the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rest of the oil in, and the dip stick happy, I was done. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t mind doing my own oil, it&amp;rsquo;s cheeper, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t take long. But man, I don&amp;rsquo;t like working on low cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone wondering what car I drive, she&amp;rsquo;s a 2015 Honda Accord EX-L, with a 2.4L i-VTECH DOHC mated to a CVT. Super fun to drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Oil%20Time&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📨&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Oil Time&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m joking, calm down.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I do rest the frame onto a jack stand, as you can see in the photo.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I put a touch of oil around the seal.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sending a Flag to Alaska - By hiding it behind a cat</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/sending-a-flag-to-alaska/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:22:39 -0400</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/sending-a-flag-to-alaska/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;One of my hobbies is geocaching. And a neat part of geocaching, is trackables. A trackable, in short, is a little trinket with a tracking code. People move trackables from cache to cache, and up date the trackable&amp;rsquo;s log online. This lets people watch, and see, where a trackable has been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few trackables in the past, but none really went anywhere. I wanted to change that, even if I had to do it myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was getting ready for my &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthp.me/tags/denver-2024/&#34;&gt;Denver 2024&lt;/a&gt; trip, I had an idea. To spread the greatest state flag in the union, Maryland. So, I grabbed a keychain flag, and a trackable tag, and made them one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made sure to take the trackable to a local-ish cache, to log that it was in Maryland. Then, I flew out to Colorado. My target was Vail resort. There were a few caches on the trails, but I picked one that was behind a big cat. Dropped it off, logged it, and went on skiing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Last Frontier&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flag was already over 1,000 miles&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from home. So imagine my surprise when someone moved it to Alaska. Traveling over 3,891 miles. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webp&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Trackable travels plotted in Google Earth Pro&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user who moved even posted a picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig2.webp&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully it keeps moving. But even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t, I&amp;rsquo;m happy with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Sending%20a%20Flag%20to%20Alaska&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📪&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Sending a Flag to Alaska&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.609344e+8 cm for the didn&amp;rsquo;t walk on the moon nations.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>New Blog - Don&#39;t worry</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/new-blog/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 13:18:14 -0400</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/new-blog/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Quick post, I&amp;rsquo;ve started a new blog! Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, nothing is happing to this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new one is solely for my progress in Factorio, one of my favorite games. You can actually see it up in the nav bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So, what&#39;s changing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this blog, nothing. The new posts won&amp;rsquo;t show up in this RSS feed, and won&amp;rsquo;t show up in the post listing page for my main blog. This new blog has its own RSS feed, and its own post listing page. Nothing on my main blog is changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where is this new blog?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right here, on nthp.me. you just have to goto &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthp.me/factorio-blog&#34;&gt;/factorio-blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20New%20Blog&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📨&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: New Blog&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Should Everything Work With Everything? - Should it?</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/should-everything-work-with-everything/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 11:44:53 -0400</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/should-everything-work-with-everything/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;With recent news, and recent laws (in some places), one idea is starting to take form. That everything, should work, with everything. But should it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People on social networks like to take things to their logical extremes&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. And not in a good way. The good way of doing it, is purely hypothetical, to find where a sweet spot&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; might be. People online, like to want the logical extreme. The two extremes in this case, are that nothing works with anything, and that everything works with everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why can&amp;rsquo;t I use an Apple Watch with my Android, Why can&amp;rsquo;t I install Android on an iPhone, why can&amp;rsquo;t I put iOS on an Android, and why the sam hell can&amp;rsquo;t I put diesel fuel in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e9JMBsHxzwU&#34;&gt;Accord&lt;/a&gt;! Everything should just work with everything!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything just works with everything, why make your product good. Why make it stand out. What&amp;rsquo;s the point in putting in more, than the minimum amount of effort needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everything, should work with everything. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say the nothing should work with anything. Like almost everything in life, the answer isn&amp;rsquo;t at either logical extreme. It&amp;rsquo;s somewhere in the middle. And a lot of people online, can&amp;rsquo;t stand that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Should%20Everything%20Work%20With%20Everything&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📫&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Should Everything Work With Everything&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the worst parts, of large scale social networks.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or range.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Getting a Hackrf - A hacky little thing</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/getting-a-hackrf/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 21:46:48 -0400</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/getting-a-hackrf/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;After over a week in shipping&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I finally got my portapack h2 in for my hackrf one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webp&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The portapack h2 installed on a hackrf one&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not done with this build yet. I have a battery in the mail so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to be tethered to a power source. And I have an all black metal case coming in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, the main things I&amp;rsquo;ve done with it are: receive ADS-B, and listen in on some NFM broadcasts (the little radios some businesses use). I am planing on doing more (and a longer blog post), just need that battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Getting%20a%20Hackrf&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📬&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Getting a Hackrf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From California to Maryland, wth USPS&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hurry Up USPS - Where&#39;s my stuff?</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/hurry-up-usps/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 12:59:14 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/hurry-up-usps/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;A about a week ago, I picked up a Hackrf One. And this thing is cool. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into what it can do here (hoping to do another post about it). At the same time, I also ordered a portapack h2. The portapack basically allows the hackrf to drive itself, without the need of a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue is, I need it to show up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig1.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Shipment history&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least its getting closer. New York isn&amp;rsquo;t too far from Maryland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Hurry%20Up%20USPS&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Hurry Up USPS&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Canada Bans the Flipper Zero - No dolphins for you</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/canada-bans-the-flipper/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 17:36:29 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/canada-bans-the-flipper/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Oh Canada, why‽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canada has banned the Flipper Zero, because of car theft…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I know, the device itself was not named in the law. However, it was named online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Criminals have been using sophisticated tools to steal cars. And Canadians are rightfully worried. 
&lt;p&gt;Today, I announced we are banning the importation, sale and use of consumer hacking devices, like flippers, used to commit these crimes.
&lt;cite&gt;François-Philippe Champagne (FPC)&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=“https://x.com/FP_Champagne/status/1755691837531078820?s=20”&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flipper Devices (makers of the Flipper Zero) responded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Dear François-Philippe,
&lt;p&gt;We’d appreciate it if you could provide any evidence of Flipper Zero being involved in any criminal activities of this kind. We’re not aware of any events like this and frankly speaking not sure what was the reason for this discussion to begin with.
&lt;cite&gt;Flipper Zero&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=“https://x.com/flipper_zero/status/1756087390974660612?s=20”&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Flipper Zero isn’t a tool used to steal cars. While yes, it does have a configurable sub-ghz radio. The Flipper, out of the box, doesn’t support rolling codes, used by car keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install third party firmware, that adds support for rolling code generation. The main issue is, in order for a Flipper with third party firmware to clone the key. You need the key. At that point, you might has well just take the key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a good video by &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/PO_o15odjkU?si=TMW4I4znCXvbeB6W&#34;&gt;Seytonic&lt;/a&gt; that goes over this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come on Canada, you can do better than this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Canada%20Bans%20the%20Flipper%20Zero&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📫&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Canada Bans the Flipper Zero&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Back to BWI - Home is the crabland</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/back-to-bwi/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 14:42:18 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/back-to-bwi/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;It started with getting to the airport, and that meant getting up at 3AM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;den---bna&#34;&gt;DEN -&amp;gt; BNA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig1.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;BWI -&gt; BNA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The airport was pretty quiet this morning. That made getting through TSA pretty quick. Though, at the entrance, the computer didn&amp;rsquo;t like my mobile ID, and threw some alerts. The agent had me try my physical ID, and that was fine, so he let me go. Can&amp;rsquo;t trust the MVA&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-food-journey&#34;&gt;The Food Journey&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This started when I got off the people-mover at C where my gate was. I got up to the main food court, and looked at my options&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. With nothing good in site, I checked a map. There was a Chick-Fil-A in B, sweet. I headed back downstairs to the people-mover, and headed off to B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got to B, I headed up to the food court, excited for some good Chick-Fil-A breakfast&amp;hellip; It was closed. Alright, most fast food places in airports open at 5AM, it was almost that time. So I whipped out my phone to double check and, it opens at 6AM&amp;hellip; My flight boards at 6:20AM, that won&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the people-mover back to C and looked at my options. C had an Auntie Anne&amp;rsquo;s, that&amp;rsquo;ll work. After a long ass walk, I arrive at the pretzel place, and it was closed. This one opened at 10AM&amp;hellip; What the hell is wrong with you DEN?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-flight&#34;&gt;The Flight&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theres not many people on this flight, around 100/147. That means that I was able to get a whole row to myself, yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bna---bwi&#34;&gt;BNA -&amp;gt; BWI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig2.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;BNA -&gt; BWI&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do love a connection, airports are cool, and I love to explore them. However, this is the worst kind of connection&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, the kind where I don&amp;rsquo;t get off the plane. I&amp;rsquo;ll take a direct flight over these. With those, I know I won&amp;rsquo;t get to explore a new airport. With this connection type, I&amp;rsquo;m so close, but so far. I did however, get to move up to the very front of the plane, as you can see in the boarding pass pics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-flight-1&#34;&gt;The Flight&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty short flight, about one hour in the air. To pass the time, I watched some plane crash documentaries, while working on this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Back%20to%20BWI&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📫&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Back to BWI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Maryland equivalent to a DMV, they issue our physical and mobile IDs.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a bite before flying is a requirement for me.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, at least.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Skiing Vail - Time to ski</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/skiing-vail/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 14:46:09 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/skiing-vail/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;It’s time to do the thing I can all this way for, ski!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vail&#34;&gt;Vail&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vail was about a two hour drive from where I was staying. So that meant I got to drive on love fantastic looking mountain roads&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig2.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A mountain road&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vail is big, like really big. Like, they have three trail maps big. I didn&amp;rsquo;t take many pics while there. So here&amp;rsquo;s one of me and my friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig1.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;I&#39;m on the left&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Skiing%20Vail&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Skiing Vail&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend drove, as I can&amp;rsquo;t drive stick.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Flying Back to Denver - Here we go again</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/flying-back-to-denver/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 07:09:03 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/flying-back-to-denver/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;The time has come, time go get up super early. My flight is scheduled to depart at 06:25, so that meant I had to be up at that time, yesterday. Why yesterday you might ask? Southwest is a first come, first serve seating airline. To control the chaos, they have three boarding groups. And depending on when you check in, determines you boarding group, and position. The sooner you check in, the better boarding spot you get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig1.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;BWI -&gt; DEN&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good ol&amp;rsquo; BWI charges to use bag carts. So I had to whole all my stuff myself. Carrying skis, polls, and boots all in one hand isn&amp;rsquo;t fun. At least they were in bags. Checking them in was easy. Southwest counts a ski bag, and boot bag, as one bag. I just had to tell the kiosk what I had, and hand them off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of this paragraph, I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for my plane. Like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthp.me/posts/flight-update-3/&#34;&gt;last time&lt;/a&gt; I flew to Denver. I loaded up a bunch of videos on my mac to watch. This time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t just grab a ton of plane crash videos. I grabbed some other stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Plane Crashes&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;BURSTING into flames seconds after takeoff - British Airways 268.mp4
Crashing SECONDS after Takeoff?! Singapore 006.mp4
Did Flight 1713 Pilots Miss a Crucial Step Before Takeoff?.mp4
HORRIFYING - all 4 engines FAILED! | British Airways flight 9.mp4
Two engines FALL OFF Boeing 747 moments after takeoff | El Al 1862.mp4
WHAT caused the WORST single air crash in history?? | Japan Air 123.mp4
What Netflix got WRONG - Malaysian Flight 370.mp4
What REALLY happened Korean Flight 007??.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Technology Connections&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;1970&amp;#39;s Camera Tech- How they showed you what settings to use.mp4
Flash photography used to be pretty wild.mp4
Movies made sound with a light bulb- Sound-on-film.mp4
Personal &amp;#34;air conditioners&amp;#34; aren&amp;#39;t what they seem.mp4
Photoelectric light controls are weirder than they seem.mp4
The correcting feature of typewriters is not what I thought.mp4
This goofy fridge has a really clever design. It&amp;#39;s also kinda terrible..mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Tech Tangents&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;1980 Terminal with Linux - TeleVideo 950.mp4
An Apple --- That &amp;#34;Just Works?&amp;#34;.mp4
DECtalk DTC01 - 1984 Speech Synthesizer.mp4
Forgotten Before Zune - Microsoft Portable Media Center.mp4
Installing FreeDOS for 8086 on an IBM 5150.mp4
Origins of the 3.5in Floppy Disk.mp4
Printing From the Past - HP 2671G Thermal Printer.mp4
USB to ISA Card Surrounded by Issues But Still Works Well.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-gate&#34;&gt;The Gate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Flight this time is a direct route. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty boring. I love exploring airports, so having a connection is big value add for me. So not having one kinda sucks. I&amp;rsquo;m also stuck on a 737-700, one of the smaller more cramped 737s. It&amp;rsquo;s almost 5AM, time to get some food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve had some food, it&amp;rsquo;s time to board. I got up at 6AM yesterday to check in on the app&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I managed to score spot B2, about as good as you can get without paying. Second in line, in the second line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flight&#34;&gt;The Flight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second spot, of the second line, at the second gate, in the second terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boarding and take off went smoothy, far better than my last flight to Denver. Glad I don&amp;rsquo;t have to add the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthp.me/tags/air-crazyness/&#34;&gt;air craziness&lt;/a&gt; tag to this post. We&amp;rsquo;ll see about my flight home. But before that, I need to ski.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Flying%20Back%20to%20Denver&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email ✉️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Flying Back to Denver&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Southwest, you have to check in to get your boarding pass. Check in starts 24h before gate departure. The sooner you check in, the better boarding position you get. Your boarding position is just you spot in line to get on the plane. Once you get on board the plane, you can take whatever seat you want.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Running Halo on an ARM Mac - Satan would be proud</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/running-halo-on-mac/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 15:52:25 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/running-halo-on-mac/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking, but I&amp;rsquo;m not pulling a fast one on you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halo the Master Chief Collection, is a windows only game. You want to play it? Buy an Xbox, or a Windows PC. However, there are ways to run windows programs on not windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valve, has been putting a lot of time, and money, into doing just that. The back bone of their Proton translations system, is WINE&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. WINE makes it possible for windows programs, to run on Linux. This allows the Steam Deck (a Linux game system), to run games like, Halo MCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mac, runs macOS. While macOS isn&amp;rsquo;t Linux, it is UNIX&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. And with how closely Linux is related to UNIX. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to port software back and forth. Because of that, WINE is available for macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-how-do-i-do-this&#34;&gt;So, how do I do this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t, Halo doesn&amp;rsquo;t run well on macOS. WINE for the mac is still pretty young.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, just in case you want to try anyway, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a couple things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An ARM mac (ie: M1, M2, M3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;macOS 14 or up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need to download &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Whisky-App/Whisky?tab=readme-ov-file&#34;&gt;Whisky&lt;/a&gt; from GitHub. This will set up and manage WINE for you. Just create a new Windows 10 bottle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the Windows version of steam, and launch the EXE. Whisky will ask you to pick what bottle you want to use, just pick your Windows 10 bottle, and hit run. Then, just install steam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you log in, just install Halo MCC. You might have to restart steam a few times, as the download can get stuck sometimes. You will have to turn the graphics down, so it won&amp;rsquo;t crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with that, you have Halo on a mac. Satan would be proud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig1.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Halo MCC&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig2.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Halo MCC, running on macOS&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/3wiTuzr_IkE?si=VsmWlqB3PdMDVHki&amp;amp;controls=0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Running%20Halo%20on%20an%20ARM%20Mac&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📨&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Running Halo on an ARM Mac&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wine Is Not an Emulator.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux is a clone of UNIX.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vision Pro Demo - I can see now!</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/vision-pro-demo/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 19:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/vision-pro-demo/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;The Apple Vision Pro has released, and I’m not buying one. I just don’t have $3,500 to drop on it. But I am super excited by the product. So, I booked a demo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Booking a demo was pretty straight forwards. I fired up the Apple Store app on my iPhone, and hit the book demo button. It then asked me where I would like to do the demo. Unfortunately, my closest store didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good time for me. My only option was the Apple Store down in Tyson&amp;rsquo;s Mall&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This is about an hours trip for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I got a time slot, it gave me check-in pass, and asked me a few questions about my eyes. Things like, do I use glasses or contacts, and do I have mono vision. But with that, I was all set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;journey&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-journey-journey&#34;&gt;The Journey &lt;a href=&#34;#journey&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my metro card loaded up, I headed off to the station. Parking mid-weekday at a DC metro station can be a pain. They have tons of spots, but you might have to walk a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After about an hour and a transfer later, I was at Tysons mall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig1.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;View from Tysons station&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, that is a wet floor sign on top of that roof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Don&#39;t believe me?&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig2.webp&#34;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Told you&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;demo&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-demo-demo&#34;&gt;The demo &lt;a href=&#34;#demo&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demo started with a face scan. This was to determine what size and shape light skirt I needed. One that was done, the Vision is brought out on a wooden platter, and you are given a tour of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you strap it on, the Vision atomically locates your eyes. It ask you to hold the crown button, and when you do, motors automatically moves the display assemblies to match your eyes. After that, you go through the eye tracking calibration. Then, you are ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demo gets going with looking at some photos. This lets you experience windows floating out in front of you, and lets you get the hang of the hand gestures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re taken through a number of photos, all of different types. First up is a regular photo, then a couple panoramas. At first, the panorama is just right in front of you, that changes when they have you put it into immersive mode. Then, the panorama wraps around you. After that, you go on to a 3D Spatial photo. Then a Spatial video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panoramas were cool, but the Spatial videos were super impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, you play around with changing your environment, and moving windows around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demo wraps up with a quick viewing of a 3D movie. All in, the demo takes about 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;thoughts&#34;/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts &lt;a href=&#34;#thoughts&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am crazy impressed. The pass through was good to the point, it was like I was looking through my ski goggles. Everything felt pretty natural as well. From the look of the windows, the 3D videos, and surprising, the ease of the gestures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am super excited to pick one up. In two or so generation. $3,500 before AppleCare+ is a little much for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Vision%20Pro%20Demo&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Vision Pro Demo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macobserver.com/analysis/the-first-apple-store-open-20-years-ago-today/&#34;&gt;first Apple Store&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Prep Run - Falling down a mountain</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/the-prep-run/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 19:57:55 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/the-prep-run/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Today was prep day. In a few weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ll be flying out to ski in the rockies. So I needed to do a warm up run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig1.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;On the lift&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was about 23F&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; at Whitetail Resort. Not my preferred skiing temperature&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but it was good enough. This being the east coast, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any snow, it was all ice. The ice coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big &amp;ldquo;snow&amp;rdquo; guns you see in the photos, don&amp;rsquo;t make snow. They make small things of ice. And they are not fun&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to ski in front of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig2.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Over the hill&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend who lives in Denver, told me to get plenty of turns in. I think I did, but I&amp;rsquo;ll find out in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20The%20Prep%20Run&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: The Prep Run&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ccccc below zero&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer a touch colder&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most people, and my camera&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Update: First Snow - There&#39;s mooooore!!!</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/first-snow-update/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 23:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/first-snow-update/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an update to my last post, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthp.me/posts/first-snow&#34;&gt;First Snow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The snow is falling faster now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig1.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;More snow!!!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Update%20First%20Snow&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email ✉️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Update First Snow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>First Snow - All wheel drive into a ditch</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/first-snow/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 19:39:58 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/first-snow/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s that time of the year. Time to crash your car off the road!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snow is falling in my neck of Maryland now. And while it looks nice, people don&amp;rsquo;t know how to drive in it. Even though it snows every year here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig2.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Snow!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that the county roads haven&amp;rsquo;t been salted yet. The state highways are fine. Just not the neighborhood roads. Getting home from work was easy, till I got off the highway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the weather for the next week. The snow will probably hang around. Most here will hate that, but I love it. I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved the look of a snow filled sky, and covered ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want it to stay, because I need to get skiing. My trip to Colorado is coming up soon, and I need to get in shape for those tall boi mountains. Subscribe to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthp.me/posts/feed.xml&#34;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; feed for that, as I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting during the trip. You can also subscribe to just the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthp.me/tags/denver-2024/&#34;&gt;Denver 2024&lt;/a&gt; tag if you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20First%20Snow&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📪&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: First Snow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Pain in the Pass - Just let me ski</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/pain-in-the-pass/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 14:29:36 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/pain-in-the-pass/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an old post from my old hidden blog. This trip will be starting soon, so I’m reposting it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m flying out in a few months to go skiing in Colorado, at Vail resort. I booked my plane tickets. Now just to get my ski pass. Vail has a, selection of passes to choose from. So many that they offer a “quiz” to find the right one for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of all the passes, I needed the day pass, but which day pass. One offers just a few resorts to choose from, another gets you more to choose from, and the most expensive one gets you all resorts (except two). Vail was only covered in the top end one. Now I had to choose if I wanted to ski on “priority days”. Then what “pass insurance” type I wanted. How many days I wanted my &lt;em&gt;day&lt;/em&gt; pass to be good for. etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened to skiing. I can just go to my local mountains and not deal with… They got by Vail, so I’d still have to go through all this… Well, at least I’ll be able to to give Vail the finger in person soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Pain%20in%20the%20Pass&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Pain in the Pass&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Why Not to go Static - I&#39;m not talking about the TV kind</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/why-not-to-go-static/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:32:43 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/why-not-to-go-static/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;If you’re just getting into blogging. The idea of a static site sounds pretty great. Crazy fast load times for your readers. Complete control over the site’s design. And anywhere from dirt cheep, to free hosting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is, you have to do all the work yourself. You might be thinking, that’s no problem, I’ll just drag and drop some elements in and be good to go, right? Nope, fire up your favorite text editor, and start typing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have no experience in web design, or scripting. Then a static site will have a monumental learning curve. For example, here’s the layout file for the page that lists all of my posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-HTML&#34; data-lang=&#34;HTML&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;{{- define &amp;#34;main&amp;#34; -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{- .Title -}} 📝&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{- .Content -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{- $counter := 0 -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{- range .Pages -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{- $counter = add $counter 1 -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	{{- if eq $counter 1 -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;center&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;Latest&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;center&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	{{- end -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;article&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;{{- .RelPermalink -}}&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{- .LinkTitle -}}&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;br&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	{{- if .Page.Params.subtitle -}}&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;sub&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;sub&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{- .Page.Params.subtitle -}}&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;sub&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;sub&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{- end -}}&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;hr&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	🏷️: 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	{{- if .Params.tags -}} 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	  {{- range .Params.tags -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	  | &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;{{ &amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;tags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010&#34;&gt;/&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;relLangURL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010&#34;&gt;}}{{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;urlize&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010&#34;&gt;}}&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{ . }}&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	  {{ end }}|
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	  {{ else }}No Tags 😢
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	  {{ end }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;br&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	⏱️: &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{ printf &amp;#34;%d&amp;#34; .ReadingTime }}&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt; minutes&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;br&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	{{- $dateMachine := .Date | time.Format &amp;#34;2006-01-02T15:04:05-07:00&amp;#34; -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	{{- $dateHuman := .Date | time.Format &amp;#34;Jan 2, 2006&amp;#34; -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	🗓️: &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;{{- $dateMachine -}}&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{- $dateHuman -}}&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;article&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{- if eq $counter 1 -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;br&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;hr&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;br&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{- end -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{- end -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;{{- end -}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be fair. Once you have a layout file that does what you want, you don’t do much with it. Maybe tinker with it every now and then. So as a better example, let’s go over something you’ll do pretty often on a blog, posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this, let’s compare two different setups. First will by my workflow (static site). And second, will be with &lt;a href=&#34;https://write.as&#34;&gt;write.as&lt;/a&gt; (a very beginner friendly platform).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-workflow&#34;&gt;My Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with opening up my text editor of choice. In this case, Nova. Once I have the project opened, the first thing I’ll do is fire up a debug server&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I have that mapped to the run button in Nova. Then, I’ll start a new post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig1.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Nova&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;I have Nova split into three panes. The left one is a file browser, middle is where I edit files, and on the right, a web browser, for viewing the output of the debug server. To make a new post, I’ll open a terminal in the middle, and run this command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new content posts/Test-Post.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will make a new file in the posts folder named Test-Post.md. It will also pre-fill the file with its front matter(information about the file).  And then, I write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I want to add a photo, oh man, that takes work. First, I get the pictures I want all in one place. Then I’ll resize them to around 1000px tall. After that I’ll run a script that converts them all to webp, and adds a touch of compression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The images will get moved to a folder for that post. In this case static/pics/Test-Post. Then I can call them in the post, with some HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-HTML&#34; data-lang=&#34;HTML&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;figure&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;fig1.webp&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;/&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;figcaption&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;Nova&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;figcaption&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;figure&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Posting the post (like everything else here) takes some work. First I’ll click the build button in Nova. This will spit out a ready to serve web directory in the public folder. Then I’ll copy the contents to another folder, and push that to GitHub. GitHub will then, redeploy my site, with the new content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig2.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;GitHub deploying my site&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a fair bit of work, just for a post. And posting is the easy part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-beginners-route&#34;&gt;The Beginners Route&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that last section is putting you off from blogging, don’t let it. A static site is just one of many way to host a blog. If you’re just getting started, let’s go over posting on &lt;a href=&#34;https://write.as&#34;&gt;write.as&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write.as is where my blog originally started. I went with it because of how easy it was to get up in running. Yes it cost a little per month, but, you don’t have to do much work because of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To write a post, you simply log in, and write. Formatting is done with markdown (a super easy to learn formatting system). If you want to add an image, you just upload it to &lt;a href=&#34;https://snap.as&#34;&gt;snap.as&lt;/a&gt; (write.as’s image host) and paste the provided markdown. When you’re ready to post, you just click post. That’s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig3.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The first version of my blog&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, you don’t have much control of how things look (you can set custom CSS). But, you also don’t have to learn web design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A static site seams like the perfect way to blog (and for many, it is). But, they take a lot of work, and head banging, to set up. But, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be your first blogging setup. No one said, you can&amp;rsquo;t switch your blog to something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Why%20Not%20to%20go%20Static&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📬&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Why Not to go Static&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will let me see how my site will look, as I work on it.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Puking in VR - It looks so real</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/puking-in-vr/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 19:08:32 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/puking-in-vr/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;I love VR. Strapping on a headset, and entering another world is truly a unique experience. You could be building something as a giant sea monster, or putting together a 3D puzzle, or playing mini golf, in space. The possibilities are endless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig1.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Building things as a giant sea monster&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig2.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Golfing in space&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of ways to get into VR. On the cheap end, you can pick up a used Meta Quest&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Or you can go super top end with a PC setup. My setup, is closer to the PC end, just without Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a PSVR2 hooked up to a PlayStation 5. The PSVR2 has a lot of features to pulled me to it. Each eye gets a 2000x2040 OLED screen, and tracking camera. That eye tracking lets the PS5 do some fancy rendering tricks, and lets you select menu items with just your eyes&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The headset also has a rumble motor, for added immersion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The controllers have touch sensitive areas, for added input. And feature the same resistive trigger as the main controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig3.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Golfing upside down&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went with the VR2 for two main reasons. VR can get crazy expensive. The Valve Index, costs $1,000. That gets you, the headset, the powered reference markers, and the controllers. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Hope you have a PC that can drive it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PSVR2 comes in at $550. Yeah, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to pick up a PS5 if you don&amp;rsquo;t have one. But, tossing in a PS5, you&amp;rsquo;ll either a tad above, or a tad bellow the price of an Index. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a VR grade gaming PC&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; So the VR2 was a no brainer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig4.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Exploring the galaxy&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VR2 was also super easy to set up. Unlike something like the Index, the VR2 has no powered reference marker to hang. And you only have one cable to plug in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setup also takes advantage of the built in eye tracking. Helping you get the IPD setting just right&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The eye tracking calibration is also super cool to play with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig5.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Working at a convenience store&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#39;fig6.webp&#39;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;About to get stabbed&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had my VR2 for a while (Got it when it came out). And it&amp;rsquo;s the reason why I picked up a PS5. While VR isn&amp;rsquo;t for everyone. It is a ton of fun. Just remember to take breaks, VR fatigue is a thing, and is not fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Puking%20in%20VR&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📨&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Puking in VR&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though, buying used VR gear is like buying used socks.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s super cool.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, people have gotten VR working on the Deck, but its really not built for that workload.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will also ask you to readjust the IPD, if the dial got moved while powered off.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Time I Broke My Foot, and Didn’t Know - The purple flesh balloon</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/broken-foot/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 12:20:13 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/broken-foot/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;It all happened while playing a game of manhunt&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This game was being played indoors, and I was running. Running away from an ambush. I was running back to the safe area, and I was running barefoot&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This, this is where I made a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have loose joints. So when kicked someone’s boot at full speed. I thought I just popped some joints in my foot. I do that all the time, no big deal. So, thinking that, I kept playing. For the next half hour, I ran, and hunted man. I stopped when my foot inflated like a balloon. A purple balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A trip to the doctor later, and I was in a boot, with a clean break in my third metatarsal. A simple clean break, just had to take it easy, and use the boot. However, that’s not all I did. After a trip to my uncles house&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (my normal doc). He took one look at my X-ray, and gave me some more news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clean break in my third metatarsal, explained the slight pain in the middle of my foot. But what about the pain on the outside of my foot. Turn out, I broke my fifth metatarsal as well. Though, I didn’t do it cleanly. I partially shattered it. Yep, that explained the pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all that, I was told one main thing. Don’t ski for six weeks. This makes sense. The bones need time to heal. And skiing can be pretty hard on joints, and bones. I was skiing at week four. Let me tell you, two broken bone ends moving around, feels pretty wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, don’t do what I did. Don’t break bones, and don’t run or ski on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened almost ten years ago, and my foot still complains every now and then. I told that’s normal, and it won’t really stop. Just another reason to not break a bone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20The%20Time%20I%20Broke%20My%20Foot%20and%20Didn’t%20Know&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: The Time I Broke My Foot and Didn’t Know&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think hide and seek, but with violence.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was running barefoot to stay quiet.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Family new years party.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Wonka</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/wonka/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 16:23:54 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/wonka/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Earlier today I went to see Wonka. A prequel to one of the Wonka movies&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. After seeing the good ratings, and loving the original. I picked up a ticket to my local Warehouse Cinema. And gave it a watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;SPOILERS!!!!&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p class=&#39;notice&#39;&gt;This is going to be a bit rambly, I&#39;ve only see the movie the once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty skeptical going in. Alright, I was very skeptical going in. I am a big fan of the original movie. So I was wondering, will this be a prequel to the original, or the 2005 film. Wonka goes for the original, both in the story(ish), and in the mannerisms of Wonka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trailer really set that, showing an orange Oompa Loompa. That Oompa Loompa, was also the only one in the movie. Well, the only speaking one&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. His role was to steal chocolate from Wonka, to replay for the coco beans Wonka stole from Loompa Land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wondering how the movie would handle the Oompa Loompa. The trailer looked promising. But in short, the movie did it absolutely perfectly. The actor, the songs, and really everything about the Oompa Loompa, was bang on perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of actors, they were all also fantastic&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Just hands down, great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The songs though, there were a lot of them. Like, a lot. None of them were bad, they were all quite good. But the Oompa Loompa ones stole the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story was, fine. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad, it was quite fun. From Wonka falling in debt due to not being able to read&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. To breaking out of a launder-mat prison. The story was fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I liked it. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t fantastic, but it was fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: If Keegan-Michael Key being chief of police sounds fun, give this a watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Wonka&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📨&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Wonka&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More on that in the spoilers.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others do appear in a flash back, though they don&amp;rsquo;t speak.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less so on the kid Noodle, but you can only expect so much from child actors.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;yes, he spent his hole life learning chocolate.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>My Regular Watches</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/my-regular-watches/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 21:40:52 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/my-regular-watches/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I made a post about all the smart watches I’ve used. In that post, I said that I would make a part two, going over all of my traditional watches. Well, this is that post. (You can read part one &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthp.me/posts/my-smart-watch-journey/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to go into why I picked up each watch. I’m just going to list each watch in my collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can click on the 🌐 emoji to go the the watch&amp;rsquo;s product page. Make sure to read the footnote if there is one. They look like this -&amp;gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. None of these are affiliate links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who look at the prices, do what I did, and buy used. You&amp;rsquo;ll save a ton if you can &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;fig8.webP&#39; width=&#39;300&#39; /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;promaster-skyhawk-a-t&#39; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;promaster-skyhawk-a-t-promaster-skyhawk-a-t&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Promaster Skyhawk A-T&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#promaster-skyhawk-a-t&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Movement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Solar&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Crystal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Saphire&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra feature&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Self Setting Time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.citizenwatch.com/us/en/product/JY8078-52L.html&#34;&gt;🌐&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;fig5.webP&#39; width=&#39;300&#39; /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;seiko-presage-sharp-edge-gmt&#39; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;seiko-presage-sharp-edge-gmt-seiko-presage-sharp-edge-gmt&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Seiko Presage Sharp Edge GMT&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#seiko-presage-sharp-edge-gmt&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Movement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Automatic&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Crystal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Saphire&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra feature&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GMT Hand&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.seikowatches.com/us-en/products/presage/spb221j1&#34;&gt;🌐&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;fig6.webP&#39; width=&#39;300&#39; /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;orient-faa02001b9&#39; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;orient-faa02001b9-orient-faa02001b9&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Orient FAA02001B9&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#orient-faa02001b9&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Movement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Automatic&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Crystal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.orientwatchusa.com/collections/sport/faa02001b9&#34;&gt;🌐&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;fig2.webP&#39; width=&#39;300&#39; /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;citizen-promaster-chrono-diver&#39; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;citizen-promaster-chrono-diver-citizen-promaster-chrono-diver&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Citizen Promaster Chrono Diver&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#citizen-promaster-chrono-diver&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Movement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Solar&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Crystal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra feature&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chronograph&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.citizenwatch.com/us/en/product/CA0710-58L.html?cgid=promaster&#34;&gt;🌐&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;fig1.webP&#39; width=&#39;300&#39; /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;orient-bambino-open-heart&#39; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;orient-bambino-open-heart-orient-bambino-open-heart&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Orient Bambino Open Heart&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#orient-bambino-open-heart&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Movement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Automatic&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Crystal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra feature&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Open Heart&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.orientwatchusa.com/collections/orient-bambino/ra-ag0005l10a&#34;&gt;🌐&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;fig3.webP&#39; width=&#39;300&#39; /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;bulova-98b212&#39; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bulova-98b212-bulova-98b212&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bulova 98B212&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#bulova-98b212&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Movement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Quartz&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Crystal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra feature&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chronograph&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chrono24.com/bulova/bulova-precisionist-diver-98b212--id25850021.htm&#34;&gt;🌐&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;fig7.webP&#39; width=&#39;300&#39; /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;orient-ra-ak0403n10a&#39; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;orient-ra-ak0403n10a-orient-ra-ak0403n10a&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Orient RA-AK0403N10A&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#orient-ra-ak0403n10a&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Movement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Automatic&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Crystal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra feature&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;24h Hand&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.orientwatchusa.com/collections/sport/ra-ak0403n10a&#34;&gt;🌐&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;fig4.webP&#39; width=&#39;300&#39; /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;seiko-5-snk793&#39; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;seiko-5-snk793-seiko-5-snk793&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;SEIKO 5 SNK793&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#seiko-5-snk793&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Movement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Automatic&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Crystal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20My%20Regular%20Watches&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email ✉️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: My Regular Watches&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello 👋&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These aren&amp;rsquo;t watches that explode in second hand value. For some, you&amp;rsquo;ll see two prices on the manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s site. The crossed out one is for 3rd party sellers (like Macys). The non crossed out one is what you&amp;rsquo;ll pay by buying direct.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This watch must be bought through a dealer, yes it was a pain.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This color way looks to be discontinued. So I linked to an all blue one.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put a different band on mine.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it on the manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s site, so here&amp;rsquo;s it on Chrono24. Note: you can get this for far less on eBay.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it on the manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s site. But you can find it for not much on eBay, and sometimes Amazon.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>My Smart Watch Journey</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/my-smart-watch-journey/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 18:09:02 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2024/my-smart-watch-journey/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I’ve worn many, many different watches. Maybe a little too many. I was thinking of doing a big blog post going over all of them. But that would be really long. So I’m breaking it up into two parts. This is part one, just Smart Watches. Part two will be on my traditional watch collection. So let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Jump To Section&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#pebble&#34;&gt;Pebble&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#pebble-steel&#34;&gt;Pebble Steel&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#pebble-time&#34;&gt;Pebble Time&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#pebble2&#34;&gt;Pebble 2&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#moto&#34;&gt;Some Moto Thing&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#back-to-pebble&#34;&gt;Back To Pebble&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#AWS2&#34;&gt;Apple Watch S2&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#AWS4&#34;&gt;Apple Watch S4&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#NSW&#34;&gt;Non Smart Watches&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#AWS7&#34;&gt;Apple Watch S7&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#AWU1&#34;&gt;Apple Watch Ultra 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p class=&#39;notice&#39;&gt; You can view a picture of the watch by clicking 📷, or watch a review from when that watch came out by clicking 🎥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;pebble&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;pebble-httpswwwandroidpolicecomwp-contentuploads201309nexusae0_pebbleblackwatchthreebuttonside_201309251030513jpg-httpswwwyoutubecomwatchvg0vuyyngeey-pebble&#34;&gt;Pebble &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/nexusae0_PebbleBlackWatchThreeButtonSide_201309251030513.jpg&#34;&gt;📷&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G0VUYyNgEEY&#34;&gt;🎥&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#pebble&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first watch. Not just my first smart watch, but my first watch. I didn&amp;rsquo;t participate in the kick starter, but I did put a pre order in on their site. I ended up canceling my pre order, and just buying one at a Best Buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pebble got so much right out of the gate. You had notification, watch apps, custom watch faces, 5-7 day battery life, and an always on display. That display was only black and white, no grey scale. But it worked, and was insanely readable in direct sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pebble was pretty fantastic, the only downside was how plasticky it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;pebble-steel&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;pebble-steel-httpbrain-imagescdndixonscom7210078727u_10078727jpg-httpswwwyoutubecomwatchvsf2etuli6uc-pebble-steel&#34;&gt;Pebble Steel &lt;a href=&#34;http://brain-images.cdn.dixons.com/7/2/10078727/u_10078727.jpg&#34;&gt;📷&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sf2EtulI6uc&#34;&gt;🎥&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#pebble-steel&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pebble Steel fixed that one main issue. It was made out of stainless steel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;pebble-time&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;pebble-time-httpscdn1vox-cdncomthumbor9podxr3jzagjvfvyrc_lry0qjwicdn0vox-cdncomuploadschorus_assetfile3439584pebble_watch_3up0png-httpswwwyoutubecomwatchvvxsuqspbyto-pebble-time&#34;&gt;Pebble Time &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9POdXR3jzAgJvFVYrC_LrY0QJwI=/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3439584/Pebble_Watch_3Up.0.png&#34;&gt;📷&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VXSUQSpBYTo&#34;&gt;🎥&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#pebble-time&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Time brought new features to the Pebble. The big one, a color screen. That fancy color screen, didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt the battery life. Still perfectly viable in sunlight, and with the same 5-7 days battery life. The Time also had a microphone, so you could dictate messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;pebble2&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;pebble-2-httpswwwbhphotovideocomimagesimages2000x2000pebble_100200064_2_heart_rate_smartwatch_1276995jpg-httpswwwyoutubecomwatchvuu1jn-ax5fg-pebble2&#34;&gt;Pebble 2 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bhphotovideo.com/images/images2000x2000/pebble_100200064_2_heart_rate_smartwatch_1276995.jpg&#34;&gt;📷&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Uu1jN-AX5Fg&#34;&gt;🎥&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#pebble2&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the first Pebble, and I was going to have the last. The Pebble 2 was a refined Pebble. It had the same black and white screen, but with the improvements of the Time. Extra storage, and that microphone. The 2 was a fantastic smart watch. But with the death of pebble, I knew I had to start looking for a replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;moto&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;some-moto-thing-moto&#34;&gt;Some Moto thing &lt;a href=&#34;#moto&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that Pebble was dead, I knew I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be able to keep using mine forever. While walking through a Best Buy, I noticed an open box Moto watch (I don&amp;rsquo;t remember what model it was). I used it for about three days before returning it. The round screen was cool, but Android Wear was not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;back-to-pebble&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;back-to-pebble-back-to-pebble&#34;&gt;Back to Pebble &lt;a href=&#34;#back-to-pebble&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not long after returning the Moto watch, Fitbit (the buyer of Pebble), announced they were going to keep the Pebble servers up for a year. This bought me plenty of time to think. Think of where I was going to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;AWS2&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;apple-watch-s2-httpswwwnetonnetsegetfileproductimageprimarytillbehorforbrukningtelefongpstillmobilensmartwatchaktivitetsarmbandapple-watch-s2-42mm-grayaluminium237166_255120_1_normal_extrajpg-httpswwwyoutubecomwatchvauiei4hrxdy-aws2&#34;&gt;Apple Watch S2 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.netonnet.se/GetFile/ProductImagePrimary/tillbehorforbrukning/telefongps/tillmobilen/smartwatchaktivitetsarmband/apple-watch-s2-42mm-grayaluminium(237166)_255120_1_Normal_Extra.jpg&#34;&gt;📷&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aUIEi4HrXDY&#34;&gt;🎥&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#AWS2&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the death of pebble, and my dislike of Android Wear at the time. I was still keeping my eyes open. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like the Apple Watch, as it had some software issues, and wasn&amp;rsquo;t water resistant. That changed when Apple announced the Series 2. The S2 brought the performance up, and added water resistance. exactly what I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going from a Pebble to an Apple Watch was pretty interesting. I could now take phone calls, send iMessages, use Siri. all on a bright color touch screen. It did take a bit to get used to charging every night, and not having an always on display. But it was nice to have a heart rate sensor that didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a drill bit&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;AWS4&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;apple-watch-s4-httpsd1f7geppf3ca7cloudfrontnetorigin3826141573050513713_1536838547_1434890jpg-httpswwwyoutubecomwatchv0nr0v1yqhimt422sppyguuzgv0cm9pdgjvcmcgu2vyawvzidq3d-aws4&#34;&gt;Apple Watch S4 &lt;a href=&#34;https://d1f7geppf3ca7.cloudfront.net/origin/382614/1573050513713_1536838547_1434890.jpg&#34;&gt;📷&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0NR0V1yQhIM&amp;amp;t=422s&amp;amp;pp=ygUUZGV0cm9pdGJvcmcgU2VyaWVzIDQ%3D&#34;&gt;🎥&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#AWS4&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Series 4 was a good leap from the 2. Larger rounded screen, better performance, and LTE support. Yes I know, LTE got added in the Series 3, but this was my first time with the feature. I thought it was kinda cool when I got it, but fell in love with the feature at a water park. I was able to keep my phone in a locker, and still stay connected to the group I was with. After that, I was sold, and have had it on every Apple Watch since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;NSW&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;non-smart-watches-nsw&#34;&gt;Non Smart Watches &lt;a href=&#34;#NSW&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was kinda fed up with smart watches at this point. The daily charging of Apple Watch, and some software annoyances were really getting to me. So I decided to stop using a smart watch, and pick up a traditional watch. This is were part 2 comes in. You can read that &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthp.me/posts/my-regular-watches/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;AWS7&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;apple-watch-s7-httpswwwtioplfotoprodukt_big1041mm_cellular_polnoc_22jpg-httpswwwyoutubecomwatchvbsosqkfa2l8ppygubyxbwbgugd2f0y2ggc2vyawvzidcgcmv2awv3-aws7&#34;&gt;Apple Watch S7 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tio.pl/foto/produkt_big/10/41mm_cellular_polnoc_2(2).jpg&#34;&gt;📷&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BsosQkfa2L8&amp;amp;pp=ygUbYXBwbGUgd2F0Y2ggc2VyaWVzIDcgcmV2aWV3&#34;&gt;🎥&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#AWS7&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple years on traditional watches, I was starting get a little board of them. So I pulled out my old Apple Watch S4 to see if the newer software fixed my complaints. In short, it did. But, If I was going back to a smart watch, it had to have an always on display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I traded in my Series 4, and picked up a Series 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The S7 brought me the additions from the S5 and 6 that I skipped. Mainly the blood oxygen sensor, and the always on display. Man did I like the AOD. The S7 also had a slightly larger display, compared to the S4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#39;AWU1&#39;/&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;apple-watch-ultra-1-httpsfdn2gsmarenacomvvpicsappleapple-watch-ultra-1jpg-httpswwwyoutubecomwatchvhjeqowjtkhe-awu1&#34;&gt;Apple Watch Ultra 1 &lt;a href=&#34;https://fdn2.gsmarena.com/vv/pics/apple/apple-watch-ultra-1.jpg&#34;&gt;📷&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HjEqOWjTkHE&#34;&gt;🎥&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#AWU1&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my current daily driver. I originally wasn’t sold on it, but after getting a deep scratch on my S7’s display, I picked one up. I was originally just going to get a stainless steel Apple Watch, as that had a sapphire crystal. But the Ultra also came with one, and was the same price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was loving that battery life right off the bat. Only having to charge every two and a half days was a big relief. Still wasn’t sold on the design. That was until I smacked it in the steel trailer tongue. The watch was fine. After that, I was sold, this thing is built like a tank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of watches. And that was only the smart watches. It&amp;rsquo;s been fun watching the market grow. And it&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see where the wearable goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20My%20Smart%20Watch%20Journey&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📪&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: My Smart Watch Journey&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at you Pebble 2&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Running on Time</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/running-on-time/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 19:23:03 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/running-on-time/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago, I took a trip down to see some family. This was an overnight trip, about four hours&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from where I live. Normally when I travel, I pack an abundance of power. Extra chargers, cables, and a big battery pack. This time though, I decided not to bring my Apple Watch charger.I use an Apple Watch Ultra 1. So a basic overnight trip should be no big deal for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started the &amp;ldquo;experiment&amp;rdquo; the night before heading out, charging up to 100%. Once it was charged, I took it off the charger&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and went to bed. Waking up, I had 95% charge. A couple hours later I headed out, sans charger. My head math said I was going to be fine, but it still felt weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At around the end of the day, I was down around 70ish%. With my trip almost over, I set my alarm, and went to sleep. When I got home the next day, I was at 50%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a good feeling this would be the result, as I&amp;rsquo;ve gone far longer on the Ultra without topping up. But it&amp;rsquo;s one thing to do a duration test when you&amp;rsquo;re always within 50 feet&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of a charger. It feels very different, when you don&amp;rsquo;t have that option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Running%20on%20Time&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Running on Time&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;175 miles, or 281 KM, for nations that haven&amp;rsquo;t walked on the moon.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the watch as my alarm clock. The best alarm is the one strapped to you.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.24 meters for nations that haven&amp;rsquo;t walked on the moon.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Christmas Haul</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/the-christmas-haul/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 17:54:03 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/the-christmas-haul/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Another year, and another Christmas. This was my first real Christmas working in loss prevention. And man, for a number of people, the worst comes out at Christmas. But I’m not here to talk about what people took&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, let’s go over what I got&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only asked for two main things, and I ended up getting both, and something extra. The main thing I got was a ski and boot bag. This will be great for my upcoming ski trip in Colorado. The other main thing I got was a Baltimore Ravens Lamar Jackson jersey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, it was a pretty calm Christmas. Nothing truly crazy at work, and I got to have dinner with some family down south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the greatest gift of all this Christmas, the Ravens beat the 49ers 33 to 19 🎉.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20The%20Christmas%20Haul&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📪&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: The Christmas Haul&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just stolen credit cards and scooters.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As gifts, I didn’t steal them.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Basic Site Template</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/a-basic-site-template/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 20:06:34 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/a-basic-site-template/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;I have two jobs, one of them is as a cybersecurity TA. One of the projects we have the students do, is to deploy a basic website in an Azure container. While they&amp;rsquo;re working on there site, we discuss the benefits of a personal site, and why they should have at least a basic one. The students can keep their site up if they want&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but Azure is pricy. So, I had an idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project gives them a starting template for their site&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The students are free to deviate from that template, but they start out with one. My thought was, with how much we say that they should have their own site. And with how much Azure can cost. Why not make a basic template for use outside of Azure&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I made &lt;code&gt;Basic Site Template&lt;/code&gt;, it’s exactly what it sounds like. My goal was to have an easy to understand template, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like crap when rendered. The template is only 39 lines, and has clear labels of what goes where.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Template index.html&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-HTML&#34; data-lang=&#34;HTML&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;lang&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;en-us&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;dir&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;ltr&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;		&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;viewport&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;width=device-width&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;		&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;link&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;rel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;stylesheet&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;https://cdn.simplecss.org/simple.min.css&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;SITE TITLE&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;		&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;header&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;SITE TITLE&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;nav&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;				&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;ul&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;					&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;li&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;						&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;LINK&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;LINK 1&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;					&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;li&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;					&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;li&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;						&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;LINK&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;LINK 2&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;					&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;li&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;				&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;ul&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;nav&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;		&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;header&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;		&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;center&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;/pics/FILENAME&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;256&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;256&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;br&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;ABOUT YOU&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;button&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;mailto:YOUR EMAIL&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;Contact Me!&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;center&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;		&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;		&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;footer&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;Copyright NAME 2024
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;				&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;br&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			Site made with &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;https://simplecss.org&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;Simple.CSS&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;			&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;		&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;footer&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;	
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned from my students, that examples go a long way. Not only did I put examples in the readme instructions, I also spun up a simple demo site. The demo site is hosted out of the demo branch, so its index file is easily viewable&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping this will help a few students get a basic landing page up. I even dropped a link to the GitHub pages docs for free hosting. I might follow this post up in a few semesters with how’s it’s gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the GitHub repo &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nathnp/Basic-Site-Template&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20A%20Basic%20Site%20Template&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📫&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: A Basic Site Template&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After grading, the student has to take up the hosting costs.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is a mixture is them writing their own site, and deploying it.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They can rip the index file out of the container if they want, however they’d also have to rip out the CSS file.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put a link to it in the readme, I know how my students can be.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>My Picky Monitor</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/my-picky-monitor/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 13:05:44 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/my-picky-monitor/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using an ultra wide monitor for quite a while. And I&amp;rsquo;m at the point where I swear by them now. However, while the model I use, is pretty great, it has one issue that makes me not want to recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lg.com/us/monitors/lg-35wn75c-b-ultrawide-monitor&#34;&gt;LG UltraWide 35WN75C&lt;/a&gt;. On paper, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty fantastic. 3440X1440 resolution, at 100Hz with AMD FreeSync support. Two HDMI ports, a DisplayPort 1.4 port, and USB-C as inputs. That USB-C port also serves as a dock, with two USB A 3.0 ports connected to it. This is exactly what I wanted. A big ass monitor, with a built in USB-C dock for my laptop. One cable for display, IO, and charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That USB-C port however, is super picky. While it works wonderfully with my M1 MacBookPro, and my FrameWork 13, it is not a big fan of my SteamDeck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, if the Deck is fully charged, it works fine&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, if the deck is not fully charged, the monitor will crash. Yes, crash. You might think, the Deck is drawing too much power. The Deck draws up to 30w. My MacBookPro, draws more than double that, from the monitor. Without issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything I’ve read online says the type C port on it is just super picky. And that’s a shame. Because it’s a nice panel. And if the type C port worked fully, I could super easily recommend it. But I just can’t, not with that issue, and not at its price tag of $600.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20My%20Picky%20Monitor&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email ✉️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: My Picky Monitor&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>My Home Lab</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/my-home-lab/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 16:05:33 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/my-home-lab/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a small home lab for a bit. Servers have come and gone, but a few core ones have remained. So let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it, and my home network as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;network&#34;&gt;Network&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the network, as that&amp;rsquo;s the backbone of the everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty much all in on UNiFi for networking. My main router is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ui.com/us/cloud-gateways/dream-router&#34;&gt;UNiFi Dream Router&lt;/a&gt;. The UDR is a home and small business router. With the usual built in switch (though two of the ports are POE), and wireless access point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UDR, also controls two dedicated access points. One being a U6-LITE, and the other being an older AC-PRO. This allows me to have one, seamless, multi AP WiFi network. That covers the whole house. Though all of my lab server are hooked up over gigabit ethernet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;home-lab&#34;&gt;Home Lab&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My home lab, is made up of four main servers. My NAS, DNS, Home Auto, and Virtualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nas&#34;&gt;NAS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My NAS is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://global.download.synology.com/download/Document/Hardware/DataSheet/DiskStation/18-year/DS418/enu/Synology_DS418_Data_Sheet_enu.pdf&#34;&gt;Synology DS418&lt;/a&gt;. Its an older four bay NAS. It&amp;rsquo;s main use is as file storage (duh), movie serving, and as a backup target for my Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A NAS is so simple, it can be kinda hard to explain. Think of it like a giant flash drive. That any computer on the network can access. Provided they have a login. A NAS can also protect your data. If the drive in your computer dies, any data you backup to the NAS, will be safe. And even if a drive in the NAS dies, no data will be lost (if you have RAID set up correctly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A NAS can also do fancy stuff, liking being the storage for a separate VM server. The VMs may get executed on one server, but all their files live elsewhere on the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dns&#34;&gt;DNS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My DNS server is a Raspberry Pi 4 running &lt;a href=&#34;https://pi-hole.net&#34;&gt;Pi-Hole&lt;/a&gt;. Pi-Hole is a network wide ad blocking server. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those server, where you just set and forget. The only main thing about the set up, is that a number of guides tell you to set the Pi-Hole&amp;rsquo;s IP, as the DNS on each of you devices. This is quite simply, shit. And really screams &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know networking&amp;rdquo;. What you really want to do. Is set the Pi-Hole&amp;rsquo;s IP as you DNS server, on your DHCP server&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (usually that&amp;rsquo;s part of your router). That way, every device on your network, will automatically use the Pi-Hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pi my Pi-Hole is running on, also has a USB to M.2 SATA board as its boot drive. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a number of SD cards and USB stick killed from Pi-Hole&amp;rsquo;s logging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;home-auto&#34;&gt;Home Auto&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My home automation server, is really more of a protocol translation server. I mainly use Apple HomeKit for everything. Automations, and manual setting of devices. The only issue is, I have a number of devices that won&amp;rsquo;t natively connect to HomeKit. Enter, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.home-assistant.io&#34;&gt;Home Assistant&lt;/a&gt;. Home Assistant manages all of my Z-Wave devices, passing their state to HomeKit. That&amp;rsquo;s really it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did use to use Home Assistant as my dedicated home auto server. But back then, Home Assistant wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that stable. It would work just happily for years, until it would shit the bed. While HomeKit is far less powerful, it&amp;rsquo;s also far more stable. That&amp;rsquo;s a trade off I&amp;rsquo;m fine with making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Home Assistant server runs on a Raspberry Pi 3+.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;virtualization&#34;&gt;Virtualization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My virtualization server, is an old ass Dell OpitPlex running &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.proxmox.com/en/proxmox-virtual-environment/overview&#34;&gt;ProxMoX VE&lt;/a&gt;. The fact that it&amp;rsquo;s old doesn&amp;rsquo;t really bother me, as I only need one or two VMs running at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main perk of a VM server, is that it let&amp;rsquo;s you offload running a VM from your local machine. This is great if you just don&amp;rsquo;t want to tank your laptop battery. Or your main computer is an ARM system, like mine. In that case, you can&amp;rsquo;t easy run an x86 VM. So having a VM server fixes that downside of daily driving an ARM computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a my newest server. So I&amp;rsquo;m still building a core use for it. But it has come in handy for demoing different linux tools students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VM server runs on a second gen Intel Core i7 4C/8T, with 16GB of ram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any home lab, this thing is always changing. Servers have come and gone. One of the old ones I used to run was a Raspberry Pi based Minecraft Java server. Might do a post on that one. I wonder what my lab / network will look like in a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20My%20Home%20Lab&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email ✉️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: My Home Lab&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make your you set it as your DHCP DNS address, and not the DNS that the router will try to use. Some ISPs won&amp;rsquo;t give you an IP unless you have the router set to their DNS, looking at you Comcast.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Deck OLED</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/deck-oled/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 11:21:40 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/deck-oled/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;A little while back, I upgraded my Deck. No, not the wooden thing on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.pinimg.com/originals/39/10/c1/3910c1cfeca4d66d3d1d403ee74940bf.gif&#34;&gt;back of a house&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about the Steam Deck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a Steam Deck for a little over a year. And over that year, the deck has gone from really cool, but needs to work. To&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Om8iSXUAKh0&#34;&gt;well&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt; Needless to say, I really like the Deck, and even upgraded mine to 2TB of storage. So when Valve announced the Deck OLED, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it looked cool as hell. And would love to have one. My first thought, was simply to build an upgrade kit from parts. Pick up a new shell, and the OLED panel (once it hit iFixit), and boom, kinda Deck OLED&amp;hellip; Valve said no. The parts are not inter-compatible. So I bought one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I caved. And I don&amp;rsquo;t regret it. The main big upgrade (being the OLED screen), is fantastic. But, there are a number of other smaller upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Deck LCD&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Deck OLED&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Screen Size&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&amp;quot;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.4&amp;quot;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Screen Refresh&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60Hz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90Hz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Battery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;40Whr&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50Whr&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CPU Node&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6nm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7nm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Weight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1lb 7.6oz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1lb 6.6oz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cup Holder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radioisotope_thermoelectric_generator&#34;&gt;RTG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;😰&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;☢️&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, not really on that last one&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most noticeable improvements, is the build quality. The Deck LCD wasn&amp;rsquo;t built poorly, but the OLED is just more sturdy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shrunk down APU, combined with the OLED screen, and the bigger battery, do wonders for battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could go on for a bit on all of the little changes, but channels like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0pBQ4dosuT0&amp;amp;pp=ygUNbHR0IGRlY2sgb2xlZA%3D%3D&#34;&gt;LTT&lt;/a&gt;, already &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uCVXqoVi6RE&amp;amp;pp=ygUNbHR0IGRlY2sgb2xlZA%3D%3D&#34;&gt;have&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1tb-is-not-enough&#34;&gt;1TB Is Not Enough&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1TB is plenty for a handheld, but I had a 2TB SSD, and I wanted to move it over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with cracking my LCD open, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/R0S8JZ6YO5c?si=Kv9rVkjzSWNLzfRY&amp;amp;t=23&#34;&gt;extracting&lt;/a&gt; the 2TB SSD. After making sure all my non cloud synced stuff was backed up, I gave it a quick format. I then moved to the OLED. Cracking that open was much nicer. The OLED uses Torx screws, vs Philips. This is great, as Torx screws don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cam_out&#34;&gt;cam out&lt;/a&gt;. With the blank 2TB SSD in the OLED, and the old 1TB SSD in an external enclosure. I was ready. I popped a clonezilla boot disk into the SD card slot, and fired it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clonezilla on the Deck is super easy to use. You can set up the whole operation with just the D-pad, and the A button&amp;hellip; You just can&amp;rsquo;t start the clone. Clonezilla is really adamant that you press &lt;kbd&gt;Y&lt;/kbd&gt; to start the clone&amp;hellip; So you need to plug in a keyboard, to press one key&amp;hellip; Great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 40 minutes into the clone. I decided to move the deck to a more powerful power adapter&amp;hellip; The moment I unplugged the cable, my docking adapter, blinked&amp;hellip; Causing clonezilla to shit itself, as the source SSD dropped off&amp;hellip; Now I had to start over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the second clone attempt was done, I fired up the Deck. After waiting for SteamOS to auto expand the partition, it was done. A 2TB handheld, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jpDL2l-MWEU&#34;&gt;in the palm of my hand&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Deck OLED is a fantastic upgrade, and I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with mine. The 90Hz screen is fantastic for Halo. And the HDR OLED, makes everything pop in ways the old Deck just couldn&amp;rsquo;t. The Deck OLED is more than just a screen upgrade. And that, is what got me to pick one up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Deck%20OLED&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📨&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Deck OLED&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Adding Tags</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/adding-tags/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 21:51:37 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/adding-tags/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;After a bit of work, a fair bit of reading, and only a few failed builds. I now have post tags working on my site. This was a lot easier than I thought. So let&amp;rsquo;s go over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four main things for adding tags in Hugo. Front matter, terms.html, taxonomy.html, and tag.html.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you have to add tags to your posts. Bellow is the front matter from my post Flight Update 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Flight-Update-3.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-MarkDown&#34; data-lang=&#34;MarkDown&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;+++
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;title = &amp;#39;Flight Update 3&amp;#39;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;date = 2023-08-21T23:33:55-05:00
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;draft = false
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;tags = [&amp;#39;Air Craziness&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Denver 2023&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Vacations&amp;#39;]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;+++
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;All this does, is tell Hugo what tags a post has. It won&amp;rsquo;t display them for the reader. This is were &lt;code&gt;terms.html&lt;/code&gt; comes in. Terms, basically puts stuff at the bottom of your posts (/pages if you want), for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;terms.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-HTML&#34; data-lang=&#34;HTML&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;{{- $page := .page }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;{{- $taxonomy := .taxonomy }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;{{- with $page.GetTerms $taxonomy }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{- $label := (index . 0).Parent.LinkTitle }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;center&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{ $label }}:&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	  {{- range . }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;		&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;button&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;{{ .RelPermalink }}&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{ .LinkTitle }}&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	  {{- end }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;center&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;{{- end }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is my terms file, that I&#39;ve modified a bit. By default, Hugo will generate a bulleted list of links for a posts tags. This looks... Bad. So, I changed the links to buttons, made the tags label a little bigger, and centered the whole thing. Much better.
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we need a page to display all of our tags. Hugo, again, has a default for this. It just doesn&amp;rsquo;t look good. By default, Hugo will use list.html to make the tags page. Most people would probably want their tags page, to look different from their posts page. This is where taxonomy.html comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxonomy.html is basically, your tags page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;taxonomy.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-HTML&#34; data-lang=&#34;HTML&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;{{ define &amp;#34;main&amp;#34; }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{ .Title }}&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{ .Content }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{ range .Pages }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;{{ .RelPermalink }}&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{ .LinkTitle }}&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{ end }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;{{ end }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is my taxonomy file. Its pretty much the same as list.html, just without the date printing stuff. So, it just makes a simple list of tags as links. Those links, will take you to a page of everything with that tag. Now we just need a page to show all posts, with a specific tag.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;tag.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-HTML&#34; data-lang=&#34;HTML&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;{{ define &amp;#34;main&amp;#34; }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;Tag: &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{ .Title }}&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;RSS link for &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{ .Title}}&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt; Tag --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;{{ .Permalink }}feed.xml&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;RSS&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{ .Content }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{ range .Pages }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;	&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;{{ .RelPermalink }}&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;{{ .LinkTitle }}&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  {{ end }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;{{ end }}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main interesting line here is line three. I have Hugo configured to generate an RSS feed for each tag. This line will generate a link to that feed. &lt;code&gt;{{ .Permalink }}&lt;/code&gt; will print out the link for the page it is on. As an example, when generating the page for the web tag, &lt;code&gt;{{ .Permalink }}&lt;/code&gt; will spit out &lt;code&gt;https://nthp.me/tags/web/&lt;/code&gt;. Tacking &lt;code&gt;feed.xml&lt;/code&gt; on the end of it, will add &lt;code&gt;feed.xml&lt;/code&gt; to the output. &lt;code&gt;https://nthp.me/tags/web/feed.xml&lt;/code&gt;. Boom, feed links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, adding tag to my Hugo site was way easier than I though it was going to be. And I was even able to set up fancy things, like per tag RSS feed links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Adding%20Tags&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📪&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Adding Tags&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Phones I&#39;ve Used</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/the-phones-ive-used/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 20:04:56 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/the-phones-ive-used/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have a number of phones. Some good, some bad. Some not even smart. So I figured, let&amp;rsquo;s go through them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;intensity&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;samsung-intensity-ii--ipod-touch-4th-gen-intensity&#34;&gt;Samsung Intensity II &amp;amp; iPod Touch 4th Gen &lt;a href=&#34;#intensity&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig0.webP&#34;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Credit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gsmarena.com/samsung_u460_intensity_ii-pictures-3450.php&#34;&gt;GSMArena&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mine was black with orange accents&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first phone I had. A basic messaging phone, with a slid-out keyboard. Now, you might be asking, how did you do anything? Games? Calendar? IM??? Simple, you carry a different device. My generation, was the last to use a separate phone and PDA. The PDA of choice at the time, was a 4th Gen iPod Touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not much to say about this combo. It was simple, and worked. It was also to norm at the time to rock two devices. However, I would make the jump&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to a smartphone, with my next upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;revolution&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lg-revolution-revolution&#34;&gt;LG Revolution &lt;a href=&#34;#revolution&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webP&#34;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Credit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gsmarena.com/lg_revolution-pictures-3732.php&#34;&gt;GSMArena&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first smartphone was an LG Revolution. The Revolution was one the worst phones I&amp;rsquo;ve used. With bad performance (though not the worst in this list), and one major safety issue. I defiantly did not have smooth entry to the smart phone world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This phone was very laggy, apps struggled to run, and things like navigation were basically impossible. But that wasn&amp;rsquo;t the worst part of it. Every now and then, the battery would get dangerously hot. To the point of getting close to burning my leg. I was actually worried that the battery might go into &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3PHbIaT-TtM&#34;&gt;thermal runaway&lt;/a&gt;. After a lot of back and forth with Verizon, I got a different phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;intuition&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lg-intuition-intuition&#34;&gt;LG Intuition &lt;a href=&#34;#intuition&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig2.webP&#34;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Credit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gsmarena.com/lg_intuition_vs950-pictures-5005.php&#34;&gt;GSMArena&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was given this phone by Verizon to replace my dangerous LG Revolution. Even though the Intuition was a newer phone, it somehow had worse performance. The home screen redrew itself every time you hit the home button. Google maps couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep up (when it didn&amp;rsquo;t crash), causing it to give me wrong turns. Oh, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have one of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unit I was given to replace my Revolution, was a &amp;ldquo;Verizon Certified Refurbished&amp;rdquo; unit, AKA, broken. It was only on my &lt;strong&gt;fourth&lt;/strong&gt; Intuition, did I get a fully &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo; one. Needless to say, I was eagerly awaiting my upgrade date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely check out this old &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jo3WYTUVNVA&amp;amp;t=347s&#34;&gt;PocketNew video&lt;/a&gt;, to see just how bad this thing is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;HTC-ONE&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;htc-one-m8-htc-one&#34;&gt;HTC One M8 &lt;a href=&#34;#HTC-ONE&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig3.webP&#34;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Credit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gsmarena.com/htc_one_(m8)-pictures-6074.php&#34;&gt;GSMArena&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That fateful morning in 2014 came, and it felt like Christmas. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what phone I was going to get, but I knew what kind. A flagship. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to take what Verizon wanted me to, I was getting something good. After looking over the show room floor for a bit, I went with the HTC ONE M8. A top of the line phone in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was very happy with it. It was was snappy, ran everything perfectly, had a really good screen, and fantastic speakers&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I used the ONE happily for a couple years, but one thing kept bugging me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updates, or how slow I got them. On carrier locked phone here in the US, android update are slow as hell. First, Google releases an update to android, then the phone manufacturer has to make sure all their stuff works on the new OS. Okay, that makes sense. But Verizon had to shove their hand into it has well. After HTC finished making the update good to go. Verizon got a say in it, and that slowed things down a lot. This, and the fact that I had recently switched to Mac, made me start looking to the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;se&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iphone-se-se&#34;&gt;iPhone SE &lt;a href=&#34;#se&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig4.webP&#34;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Credit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gsmarena.com/apple_iphone_se-pictures-7969.php&#34;&gt;GSMArena&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanting to update at the same time as everyone else, and wanting something that worked better with my then new Mac&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I made the jump, to the iPhone. A platform jump is never a small one, and I knew that going in. I got my contacts moved over, installed all my main apps that had an iOS version, synced my music over. It took all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first impressions was how far iOS had come since I last used it (iOS 6 on an iPod Touch). iOS 9, while still somewhat simplistic, was very coherent. And I liked that. The small size (and small battery), did got annoying after awhile. But, I really liked the phone, and how well it worked with my mac. And needless to say, my friends were happy that I was now a blue bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;x&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iphone-x-x&#34;&gt;iPhone X &lt;a href=&#34;#x&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig5.webP&#34;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Credit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gsmarena.com/apple_iphone_x-pictures-8858.php&#34;&gt;GSMArena&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching the launch of the iPhone X, I knew I wanted one. There was just one small problem. I was still on my two year contract with Verizon for my SE. So I went to the Verizon store to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had payed off enough of my SE that Verizon was happy to let me upgrade early. I just had to make a 20% down payment on the X. My plan was to buy the phone in full, but big red&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; had other ideas. Turns out Verizon doesn&amp;rsquo;t let you just buy outright. So I had to make the down payment, then pay it off on my first bill. Fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right off the bat, I was loving the bigger screen. It was bright, vivid, and beautiful. The rounded edges that blended into the glass felt great. And FaceID was the cherry on top. I loved this phone. and to this date, it&amp;rsquo;s the phone I&amp;rsquo;ve used the longest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;12pro&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iphone-12-pro-12pro&#34;&gt;iPhone 12 Pro &lt;a href=&#34;#12pro&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig6.webP&#34;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Credit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gsmarena.com/apple_iphone_12_pro-pictures-10508.php&#34;&gt;GSMArena&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started off not wanting to get the 12. My X is still fantastic, I just had a fresh battery put in it, I&amp;rsquo;ll just skip the 12&amp;hellip; and then came the Apple event. The &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; flat sides, bigger battery, and more capable cameras had me. To the point where not only did I buy one on pre order day, I was quick enough that it showed up on launch day. This was also my foray into buying unlocked. Something I put off for far too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bigger battery helped a ton. I was able to comfortably make it through a work day. Vs just on the X (even after the battery change). The flat sides felt great, and the faster FaceID was very welcome. Overall, my favorite thing about this phone, is that I got it day one. The only issue I had, was that the screen wouldn&amp;rsquo;t turn fully off when showing black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;14pro&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iphone-14-pro-14pro&#34;&gt;iPhone 14 Pro &lt;a href=&#34;#14pro&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig7.webP&#34;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Credit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gsmarena.com/apple_iphone_14_pro-pictures-11860.php&#34;&gt;GSMArena&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Apple showing off the new 48Mpx camera, and the fancy dynamic island, I was intrigued. But waited a bit before upgrading. But once I did, I did not regret it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in love with the new camera after the first photo I took. The photos I took were up there&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with my DJI Mavic air 2&amp;rsquo;s camera. It was just more flexible than the Mavic, and you don&amp;rsquo;t need a license to use it. Check out my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/197704187@N04/albums&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt; to see some photos from this phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dynamic island was pretty useful out the gate for me (once the 3rd party API dropped). Having live NFL and NHL scores up there, was great. It became a truly fantastic feature on my next flight though. The ability to have gate assignment, and time till gate departure, on my screen at all times, was a killer for me. Overall, I am very happy with this phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ratings&#34;&gt;Ratings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a good amount of phones. So let&amp;rsquo;s rate them on a scale of 1 - 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: I&amp;rsquo;m only going to rate the smart phones&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;aside&gt;
		Scale&lt;br&gt;
		1 --- 5 ---- 10&lt;br&gt;
		Shit  Neutral  Great
	&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Phone&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Rating&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LG Revolution&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;🔥1🔥&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LG Intuition&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HTC One M8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;iPhone SE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;iPhone X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;iPhone 12 Pro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;iPhone 14 Pro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20The%20Phones%20I&#39;ve%20Used&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📨&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: The Phones I&amp;rsquo;ve Used&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the jump to a smartphone was a big deal back in high school.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoomSound&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 13&amp;quot; rMBP&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not Target, don&amp;rsquo;t bite me &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bullseye_(mascot)?wprov=sfti1#&#34;&gt;Bullseye&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get it&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>New Road Who This</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/new-road-who-this/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 15:01:05 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/new-road-who-this/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Over the past few days, the road outside my house has had some work done to it. What kind of work you may ask? Pot hole filling? Man hole maintenance? Painting? No to all of those. They have been replacing the road… all of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	I live in an unincorporated place, so roads are managed directly by the county.
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This started like all not fun things. A notice from the county. The notice in short said that works would begin, on or around the listed date, and that the road would not be closed during the work. It also gave instructions on how to drive (and who to listen to) while the workers are paving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work started with the milling. Oh god, the milling. The entire circle had the first half inch or so milled off. This process, shook the house. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that loud. I live under a major airway for the DC area. The planes lining up for the airport can make more noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the milling, there was a few days break.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Every now and then a sweeping truck would go by, but that was it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days after that, it was time for &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/k26hmRbDQFw?si=xLNsED1u0Mi3zxzI&amp;amp;t=119&#34;&gt;paving&lt;/a&gt;. This was another house shaking process. Thankfully a quick one. I also had an idea for this. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be cool to get an a top down time-lapse of it? If only I knew a commercially licensed remote pilot&amp;hellip; oh wait, that&amp;rsquo;s me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;gif1.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;gif2.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is absolutely fascinating to watch. I really need to make more time-lapses of construction work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have gotten the chance to drive on the fresh asphalt, it was fantastic. Hopefully they finish soon. I would like to not be woken up in the morning with jackhammers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20New%20Road%20Who%20This&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📫&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: New Road Who This&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least on my stretch&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Writing a Post - No pencil needed</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/writing-a-post/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 18:24:27 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/writing-a-post/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Posting on a static site is interesting. You don’t fire up a website and start typing. Nor do you just drag and drop photos. You have to make the whole web page, yourself. It’s not that hard. Though, it can be confusing if you’re used to a CMS. Here’s my work flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I start off by firing up &lt;a href=&#34;https://nova.app&#34;&gt;Nova&lt;/a&gt;. In it I have three projects for this site. Dev, Pub, and Prod. Dev, is where I do all my work. Pub, is a public snapshot of Dev that gets updated when changes are pushed to Prod. Prod, is production. This is where Github serves the site from. Pushing changes to here will cause Github to automatically redeploy the site, with those changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drafts are written in Dev, so I open up that project. I start off by running the command &lt;code&gt;hugo new content posts/&amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;.md&lt;/code&gt;. Why do this rather than just making a new file? Simple, running this will pre-fill the file with stuff I don’t want to type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;Markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;+++
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;title = &amp;#39;Writing a Post&amp;#39;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;date = 2023-11-14T17:19:27-05:00
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;draft = true
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;+++
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;!!ADD PUB DATE!! &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;br&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;!!SET FRONTMATTER PUB DATE!! &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;br&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;!!SET DRAFT FLAG!!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are two main things here. The first is at the top. That&amp;rsquo;s the front mater for this post. It basically tells Hugo about the post. Title, publishing date, and whether or not it it’s a draft. The second thing, is a bunch of reminders. These remind me to 1. Set the publishing date on the page. 2. Set the publishing date in the front mater. And 3. Set the draft flag so it can be published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the file is created, I then run &lt;code&gt;hugo server -D&lt;/code&gt;. This will start a local web server with my site. That way I can see exactly how my post will look, before I push it to Prod. And then, I write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post files are written in Markdown. A super easy to learn (and read) markup language. You can see an example by looking at this site’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nathnp/Nathans-site&#34;&gt;public repo&lt;/a&gt; on Github. Things get a little interesting when it comes to images, and replies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-images&#34;&gt;Adding Images&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images can be a minor pain at first, till you get the hang of it. First, you need an image. In Hugo, images go in the &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; folder. To help with organization, I also use sub folders. &lt;code&gt;static/pics/&amp;lt;post name&amp;gt;/&lt;/code&gt;. Pictures will get named &lt;code&gt;fig&amp;lt;number&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, and gifs will get named &lt;code&gt;gif&amp;lt;number&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Now I can easily call the image using Markdown in the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;![](/posts/writing-a-post/fig1.webP)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;![](/posts/writing-a-post/gif1.gif)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;replies&#34;&gt;Replies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the nature of a static site, comments are a monster pain to do. So many don’t. Besides, who wants to moderate them anyway. So most blogs will have a reply by email button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is added with some simple HTML. Though you might be thinking, that sounds like a pain to put at the end of every post. Well, we can automate its generation. I made a simple Shortcut on my Mac to do exactly that. All I have to do is run it, give it the title, and it will plop ready to paste HTML, into my clipboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-HTML&#34; data-lang=&#34;HTML&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;center&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;button&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Writing%20a%20Post&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;For Webmail Users &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;br&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Address: &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;br&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Subject: &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;RE: Writing a Post&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;center&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;proofreading&#34;&gt;Proofreading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proofreading, sucks. I’ll read over a post two to three times. Correcting errors each pass through, and still find some until after posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;posting&#34;&gt;Posting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posting isn’t as simple as just clicking a post button. I need to turn this MD file, into a full blown HTML file. This is easy. All I have to do, is run the command &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt;. Hugo will then spit out my site, ready to serve in the &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; folder. Then I copy then contents of public folder to Prod. Everything else in Dev will get copied over to Pub. After that, I push both up to Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prod is the only one that does something special. When Github sees a new commit in that repo. It’ll copy all the files into a container, and deploy the site from there. All automatically. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah. This all sounds pretty complicated when you break it down. But in practice, it’s actually pretty straightforward. And you can automate all of the repetitive stuff away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blog post, about writing a blog post. Weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Writing%20a%20Post&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Writing a Post&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing there, don’t bother looking.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing here at all, I promise&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>My New Old Webcam</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/my-new-old-webcam/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 17:17:57 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/my-new-old-webcam/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had an Analogue Pocket for a while now. If you don&amp;rsquo;t known what the Pocket is, it’s a handheld FPGA game system. Capable of replicating a ton of old game systems. You can learn more about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.analogue.co/pocket&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. One neat thing about the Pocket, it has a GB / GBA slot on it. I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing GBA games on it since I got it. But only recently, did I pick up its dock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dock, let&amp;rsquo;s you plug it into a TV. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Alright, it also has two USB ports on it, and let&amp;rsquo;s you connect a bunch of different wireless controllers. After using the dock for a few days, I had an idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite a while back. People were sharing an article about how a dude used a GameBoy Camera for Zoom. There was nothing really special about it. He was using a Pocket, its dock, and a cheap capture card. So I bought a cheap capture card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webP&#34;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Taken using macOS Photo Booth&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a little concerned about the adaptor. It was shocking light. To the point I didn&amp;rsquo;t think It was going to work. But somewhat to my surprise, it did, and it looked pretty good. I work two jobs. One in loss prevention, and the other as a cybersecurity TA. The latter of the two is a remote job. And perfect for this type of thing. I&amp;rsquo;m defiantly looking forward to using it there, when I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20My%20New%20Old%20Webcam&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📫&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: My New Old Webcam&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Being Lazy With Shortcuts</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/being-lazy-with-shortcuts/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 17:51:01 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/being-lazy-with-shortcuts/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of every post. I have a reply via email button. This button does three main things. 1. It opens your default email client, 2. It pre fills the To field for you, and 3. It pre fills the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the HTML for the reply button in this post&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-HTML&#34; data-lang=&#34;HTML&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;center&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;button&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Being%20Lazy%20With%20Shortcuts&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt; Reply to this post via email 📫&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;center&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty simple, but if you look, there are a couple of things that make it a slight pain. If you look at the &lt;code&gt;?subject=&lt;/code&gt; part, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice a lot of &lt;code&gt;%20&lt;/code&gt;s. This is because you can&amp;rsquo;t have a space in a url. The other thing you might notice. Is that there&amp;rsquo;s an emoji at the end. What&amp;rsquo;s so painful about that? If you look at my other posts, they each have a different emoji, on the reply button. This combination, makes it pain to add. So I wrote a shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shortcut is pretty simple. It asks for the subject, and replaces the spaces, with &lt;code&gt;%20&lt;/code&gt;s. It then will randomly select a mail themed emoji from an internal list. Finally, it copies the output to my clipboard. Then all I have to do, is paste it into Nova.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to use this shortcut, you can click this button to add it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/bcfb8006db024bbcab2b006797a8b033&#34;&gt; Add Shortcut &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Being%20Lazy%20With%20Shortcuts&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📪&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Being Lazy With Shortcuts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>My Website Journey</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/my-website-journey/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 01:07:04 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/my-website-journey/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a blog for a few years now. And over those few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve used a number of different hosting providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve recently moved to a new blogging set up. I decided, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look back. At how I used to host this site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;writeas&#34;&gt;Write.as&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	During this time, my blog was on &lt;code&gt;blog.sulairris.com&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out my blogging adventure using Write.as. Write.as made getting started super easy. I made an account, and boom, I had a blog. For only $9/month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write.as was pretty good. However, It&amp;rsquo;s pretty limited on customization. After a couple of years on it, I started looking around at other options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wordpress&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	When moving to Wordpress, I moved my site to just &lt;code&gt;sulairris.com&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go over to Wordpress. This move started with setting up an account on Wordpress.com. This didn&amp;rsquo;t last long. As they never got my SSL cert set up. I ended up running Wordpress on a Debian VM. That VM, was one of Linode&amp;rsquo;s Nanode VMs. The Nanode is a super tiny VM, that only costs $5/month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	I later rebuilt my site under a new domain, &lt;code&gt;nthp.me&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wordpress starting getting on my nerves pretty quick. Wordpress is very, very good, at getting in the way. Over time, this just got more, and more, annoying. Around this time as well, I want to be able to post from my phone. Wordpress had a mobile app, neat. That app however, needed a plugin installed. A plugin that wanted a Wordpress.com account&amp;hellip; No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;blot&#34;&gt;Blot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	I used to have a second RSS only blog on Blot, at &lt;code&gt;rss.nthp.me&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With wanting a more easy way to post from my phone, and less overhead. I started looking around at web hosts again. After seeing a post from &lt;a href=&#34;https://kevquirk.com/moving-from-jekyll-to-blot&#34;&gt;Kev&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to check out blot. Blot very quickly got my attention. Everything is done in Markdown, and synced over Git. This meant that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with Wordpress. I could also post from my phone using a mobile Git client. Neat. And the cherry on top, it was only $4/month. One dollar less than Linode. However, I started running into a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you send MD files to blot, blot will cache the files, and build a site out of them. Every now and then, that cache would get stuck. You could push new files, but they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t appear on the visible site. The only way I had to force the cache to refresh, was to email the dev. This made me start looking again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-present&#34;&gt;The Present&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going into all the different tools I looked at. That can be a whole blog post on it&amp;rsquo;s own. And I already kinda wrote it. You can read that &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthp.me/posts/new-new-site/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This site, is using three main components. Hugo, Simple.CSS, and Github Pages. Hugo is what generates my site. When I want to make a post. I write it as an MD file. Then I have have Hugo generate the entire website. Boom, website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, that website would look, kinda bad. To make the site site look better, I use Simple.CSS. Simple.CSS is great for two main reasons. 1. It look pretty good and professional. And 2. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to learn CSS to use it, and that makes my happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike with the previous systems. That fancy site I made, lives only on my Mac&amp;hellip; That&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; kinda an issue. Lucky I had a couple of options. I ended up going with Github Pages, as I already use Github, and it&amp;rsquo;s free. Yep, free static site hosting. This dropped my costs for my blog from $4/month, to nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thoughts-on-all-this&#34;&gt;Thoughts On All This&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve moved around a lot. And because of that, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned of a number of good hosts. How to spin up a Wordpress VM in the cloud. A number of static site generator tools. And started learning about Github Actions. But, my favorite thing I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from all this. Is how to set up a fully featured site / blog, for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20My%20Website%20Journey&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📬&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: My Website Journey&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Default Things 2023</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/default-things-2023/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 18:17:38 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/default-things-2023/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Over the past few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing a lot of posts in my RSS reader. A number of people are posting what their go to apps and things are for the end of 2023. So I decided, why not add to it. Here are my default things for the end of 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail Client: Apple Mail &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail Server: iCloud Mail + Simple Login &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes: Apple Notes &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Site: Hugo + Simple.css hosted on Github Pages &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password Management: 1Password &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS: NetNewsWire &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather: Apple Weather &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maps: Apple Maps &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud Storage: iCloud + Synology DS418 &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backups: macOS Time Machine on Synology DS418&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastodon Client: Mona &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chat: iMessage &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text Editor: Nova &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FTP Client: Tansmit 5 &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podcasts: Overcast &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video Editor: Final Cut Pro &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clipboard History: Pastebot &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser: Safari &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terminal: Apple Terminal &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shell: ZSH + OhMyZSH &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git Client: Nova + Git CLI &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone: iPhone 14 Pro &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch: Apple Watch Ultra &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laptop: Late 2020 M1 MacBook Pro w/ 16GB RAM &amp;amp; 512GB Storage &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Car: 2015 &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/w9KYDQry2nQ&#34;&gt;Honda&lt;/a&gt; Accord Coupe EX-L w/ 2.4L I-VTEC w/ CVT &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Default%20Things%202023&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📪&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Default Things 2023&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>You Need a Website</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/you-need-a-website/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/you-need-a-website/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Jump to: &lt;a href=&#34;#need&#34;&gt;What You Need&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#domain&#34;&gt;Domain&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#host&#34;&gt;Host&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#site&#34;&gt;Site&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#what-i-use&#34;&gt;What I Use&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need a website, plane and simple. But why, you might ask? &lt;br&gt;
A website, is a place to call your own. A place to make your own. And a place to show off, you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a site, not only looks more professional, but also helps you show off your skills, and hobbies. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to have a blog to do this. Even a simple landing page (like my home page), can say a lot about you. Starting a site also isn&amp;rsquo;t hard. You&amp;rsquo;ll just need a few things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;need&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-you-need-need&#34;&gt;What You Need &lt;a href=&#34;#need&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
	Some hosts will take care of the site part for you.
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need three basic things for your site. A domain (ie a name for your site), A site, and a host for that site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;domain&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-domain-domain&#34;&gt;A Domain &lt;a href=&#34;#domain&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A domain, is how people will get to your site. Take mine for example. &lt;code&gt;nthp.me&lt;/code&gt;. A domain is made of two main parts. a second level domain (SLD), and a top level domain (TLD). &lt;code&gt;SLD.TLD&lt;/code&gt;. The SLD is the main part you look for when buying a domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a few domain as an example. My domain &lt;code&gt;nthp.me&lt;/code&gt;, the SLD is &lt;code&gt;nthp&lt;/code&gt;. and the TLD is &lt;code&gt;.me&lt;/code&gt;. And with &lt;code&gt;github.com&lt;/code&gt;. SLD &lt;code&gt;github&lt;/code&gt;, TLD, &lt;code&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt;. When buying a domain, most people will pick out an SLD. Then, see what TLDs have that SLD available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying a domain is pretty easy. You just go to a registrar. Pick an available domain you like. Fill out the paperwork. Pay, and you&amp;rsquo;re done. That domain is now your&amp;rsquo;s, for one year. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, your registrar will auto renew the domain for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most domains cost around $10 - $30 per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;host&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-host-host&#34;&gt;A Host &lt;a href=&#34;#host&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A host is just the service that makes your site available on the web. Most web hosts combine the &lt;a href=&#34;#site&#34;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;#host&#34;&gt;host&lt;/a&gt; sections into one. Some however, do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosting comes in a wide rage of prices, and capabilities. You can pay anywhere from $18/month for a beginner friendly host. All the way down to $0/month (yes, really), if you&amp;rsquo;re down to do a lot of it yourself. If you are fine with paying a little per month. There are two good options for around $5/month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;wordpress&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wordpress comes in two main flavors. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.com&#34;&gt;software as a service version&lt;/a&gt;. And the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org&#34;&gt;Self host-able version&lt;/a&gt;. With the SaaS version, Wordpress will do the hosting for you. This starts at $6/month. Though, if you want more features, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay more per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Self host-able version, is free. You just need to host it yourself. A good and cheep way to do this, is by using &lt;a href=&#34;https://linode.com&#34;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s nanode server plan. The nanode only costs $5/month. Linode also has a Wordpress install script. Just fill out the form, and boom, Wordpress!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;blotim&#34;&gt;Blot.im&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blot.im&#34;&gt;Blot&lt;/a&gt; is a simple web host. You write some files using Markdown. Sync those to Blot, and you have a site. Unlike Wordpress SaaS, blot doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any feature tiers. $4/month will get you everything it has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-free-way&#34;&gt;The Free Way&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web hosts that don&amp;rsquo;t charge, usually do only that. Host. You&amp;rsquo;ll need ⬇️⬇️⬇️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;site&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-site-site&#34;&gt;A Site &lt;a href=&#34;#site&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you choose a host that makes you bring your own site. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to make one on your own. You have two main options for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do it all by hand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use a static site generator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generally don&amp;rsquo;t recommend number one, if you want something more than a single page site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want something bigger than a single page site. I highly recommend you use a static site generator (SSG). A static site generator, takes easy to write files (usually Markdown), and turn them into a ready to go site. There are three main ones to choose from. &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.11ty.dev&#34;&gt;11ty&lt;/a&gt;. Of these, I would recommend starting out with either Jekyll, or Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-i-use&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-i-use-what-i-use&#34;&gt;What I use &lt;a href=&#34;#what-i-use&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is generated using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; locally on my Mac. For hosting I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. This combo allows me a lot of flexibility on how I want my site to look. The main downside, is I have to do almost all the work my self. The upside to that. This site costs me $0/month to host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;links-to-start-your-journey-links&#34;&gt;Links To Start Your Journey &lt;a href=&#34;#links&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;domain-registrar&#34;&gt;Domain Registrar&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hover.com&#34;&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;- What I use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.godaddy.com&#34;&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;site-generators&#34;&gt;Site Generators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;- What I use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.11ty.dev&#34;&gt;11ty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;web-hosts&#34;&gt;Web Hosts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;- What I use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/pages/&#34;&gt;Gitlab Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blot.im&#34;&gt;Blot.im&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org&#34;&gt;Wordpress Selfhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.com&#34;&gt;Wordpress SaaS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: &lt;strong&gt;None&lt;/strong&gt; of these links are affiliate links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20You%20Need%20a%20Website&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📨&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: You Need a Website&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Pen-Pal Thing</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/pen-pal-things/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 17:39:18 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/pen-pal-things/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Recently, Kev posted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://kevquirk.com/seeking-pen-pals&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about wanting pen-pals. He posed an a simple plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in taking part, drop me an email using the reply button at the bottom of this post. &lt;br&gt;
We can then agree on a month that works for the pair of us. &lt;br&gt;
At the start of that month (I&amp;rsquo;ll remind you closer to the time), you send me an email introducing yourself, asking a few questions blah blah, whatever you want. &lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ll then reply that same week and will publish the conversation on this blog for others to enjoy too. &lt;br&gt;
If you have a blog, feel free to do the same. &lt;br&gt;
We will continue this process for the rest of the month, and (hopefully) part ways at the end as friends&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This got my interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of his post. He had a table of months, and people. I noticed that April 2024 was open. So I shot  an email&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m down for April, as that’s also my birthday month. It’ll be cool to chat with someone in the UK who’s also in the security field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quickly got an email back. Confirming April. Sick! I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to this, and will post the email convocation on my site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Pen-Pal%20Thing&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Pen-Pal Thing&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>New New Site - Now with more static</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/new-new-site/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/new-new-site/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Welp, this was a pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few days, I have been working on moving my website. Why you might ask? Let&amp;rsquo;s go over that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while, I was hosting this site on &lt;a href=&#34;https://blot.im&#34;&gt;blot.im&lt;/a&gt;. Blot basically takes a bunch of markdown files you send them, and turns them into a website. I was a big fan of this. Simple, easy, and flexible. However, I started running into problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you send MD files to blot, blot will cache the files, and build a site out of them. Every now and then, that cache would get stuck. You could push new files, but they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t appear on the visible site. The only way I had to force the cache to refresh, was to email the dev.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving-to-something-new&#34;&gt;Moving to Something New&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some thinking, I decided to go with a static site. I&amp;rsquo;ll generate the site on my mac, then push it to a host. The first tool I tried out was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.11ty.dev&#34;&gt;11ty&lt;/a&gt; After a bunch of work, I got a super basic site up and running with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.11ty.dev&#34;&gt;11ty&lt;/a&gt; However, I didn&amp;rsquo;t like it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.11ty.dev&#34;&gt;11ty&lt;/a&gt; is written in Java Script, and I really don&amp;rsquo;t like Java Script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next tool I tried was &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll looked way nicer to work with. There was just one tiny problem. Ruby 3.1.3 didn&amp;rsquo;t want to compile on my mac. So that was out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tool that I went with (as you can see in the footer), is &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. Hugo, ships as a Go binary. This fixes the issue I had with Jekyll, and 11ty. Nothing to compile, and it&amp;rsquo;s not Java Script. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into how to use Hugo, as I&amp;rsquo;m still learning it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for hosting, I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. All I have to do, is drop the built site into a folder. and push that to Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part of all of this. My hosting costs have gone from $4/month, to $0/month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not done yet. The main thing remaining to to move all of my old posts over. That&amp;rsquo;s going to take a bit. I&amp;rsquo;ll get there though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20New%20New%20Site&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email ✉️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: New New Site&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Stealth Flipper</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/stealth-flipper/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 12:30:42 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/stealth-flipper/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, most flipper users use the flipper to dick around. You know, pop Tesla charge covers, set off CVS alcohol announcements (Bonus points if you do it in a state CVS can&amp;rsquo;t sell alcohol in (Like Maryland)). You know, fun stuff. The Flipper is unfortunately recognizable (Thanks to dumpsters like TikTok). So, if we&amp;rsquo;re going to have some fun in a CVS, or a Tesla store, we need to be a bit sneaky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: This post doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover Android, as I don&amp;rsquo;t use that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t use this post to do illegal stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Flipper iOS app supports something super handy, Shortcuts. With an Apple Shortcuts, you can remotely tell the flipper to run a .sub file. Alright, so I can fire off a transmission form my phone, so what? I can just use the flipper app. He comes the best part of using a shortcut, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to get your phone out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apple watch Ultra, has a big orange button on the side&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This button (called the action button&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) can be set to do a few things. Start a spot watch, start a work out, start a dive, etc. One of the options available, is to launch a shortcut. So, all you have to do, is make a basic shortcut&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, that runs a sub file. Set the action button to run that. And Boom, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to rock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have fun ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;gif.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Stealth%20Flipper&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📬&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Stealth Flipper&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 15 Pro also has one. And can also do this.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig2.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Making a Fast As Hell Flash Drive</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/fast-flashdrive/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 10:26:18 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/fast-flashdrive/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;A while back, I upgraded the storage in my Steam Deck. Going from 512GB, to 2TB. The upgrade was so worth it. But, as a result, I had a 512GB SSD just sitting around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a while, I ended up ordering an NVME SSD enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After chucking the SSD in there, and formatting it. I now have a little, fast as hell, USB drive. That I can also use if I need to image other NVME drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig2.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Making%20a%20Fast%20As%20Hell%20Flash%20Drive&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📫&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Making a Fast As Hell Flash Drive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Turning Off Analytics For Now</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/turning-off-analytics/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 22:51:17 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/turning-off-analytics/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;For the past month, I&amp;rsquo;ve been running analytics on both of my websites. The service I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for this is &lt;a href=&#34;https://plausible.io/&#34;&gt;Plausible.io&lt;/a&gt;. I went with them for a couple of reasons. Mainly, they didn&amp;rsquo;t look hungry for personal data. I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying them quite a lot. They have a good, very easy to use interface. That&amp;rsquo;s also not over whelming. But, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be turning analytics off, at least for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-started&#34;&gt;Why I started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started using analytics to simply see how many people were going to my site. As well as from what countries. The UK, Poland, Romania, and Czechia, are just a few that have visited my main site. That&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-im-stopping-for-now&#34;&gt;Why I&amp;rsquo;m stopping, for now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Price. That&amp;rsquo;s it really. I have enjoyed Plausible, and still really like them. However I&amp;rsquo;m coming up on the end of my free month. And will have to start paying $9/month. Now, I could switch to a different analytics provider. But, I&amp;rsquo;m not big on a lot of the others I&amp;rsquo;ve looked at. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be one of those sites, that vacuums up every possible bit of user data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do plan on firing analytics back up down the line though. Plausible is open source, and you can host it yourself. Something I will do at some point. (You can even run it on a Pi with some work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah. Plausible has been good and I like it. But it&amp;rsquo;s not really worth $9/month to have them host it. At least for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Turning%20Off%20Analytics%20For%20Now&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Turning Off Analytics For Now&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>System Source Museum</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/system-source-museum/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:18:56 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/system-source-museum/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Jump to: &lt;a href=&#34;#trip&#34;&gt;The Trip&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#museum&#34;&gt;The Museum&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#g15&#34;&gt;G15&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Quick Links: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/197704187@N04/albums/72177720312149715/with/53281603158/&#34;&gt;Flickr Album&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://museum.syssrc.com&#34;&gt;Museum Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago, I went to a bucket list level computer museum here in Maryland. A few weeks ago, a Youtube channel that I watch &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@UsagiElectric&#34;&gt;Usagi Electric&lt;/a&gt;, has been working on an old 1950&amp;rsquo;s computer (on loan for repair from the museum), and announced that he would be at the museum to swap out a part. He also said, that it would also be a meet and greet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;trip&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-trip-trip&#34;&gt;The Trip &lt;a href=&#34;#trip&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been planning on going to the museum for a bit. I was putting it off simply because it was a one hour drive (Yeah, I can be a little lazy). However, when Usagi released a video saying the Museum will be having an open house, and that he would be there swapping a part out on a Bindix G15&amp;hellip; I had to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;museum&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-museum-museum&#34;&gt;The Museum &lt;a href=&#34;#museum&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an hours drive, I pulled into the museum just outside Baltimore &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The open house started with a tour. We first went to the Cray room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;cray&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cray-room-cray&#34;&gt;Cray Room &lt;a href=&#34;#cray&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cray room had, well, Cray super computers in it. The main show pice was a Cray 1. They also had a section of a Cray 2. The Cray 2 was submersion cooled. The coolant used for it (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.3m.com/3M/en_US/p/d/b40045180/&#34;&gt;Fluorinert&lt;/a&gt;) costs around $1,000 per gallon. And they had a jar of the stuff. They were also crazy enough to let us hold it. The stuff is dense. A US gallon of water weighs about 8.33 LBs. A gallon of Fluorinert weighs about 14.66 LBs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt;Photo&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig2.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;dec&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dec-room-dec&#34;&gt;DEC Room &lt;a href=&#34;#dec&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Cray room, we moved on to the DEC room. In the DEC room was one of the first computers available. The LINC. The crazy thing about the LINC, is that not only is the chick who wrote the operating system for it, a Marylander. She also helped the museum, get theirs up and running. They also had a (mostly) working PDP 8/1. As well as a &amp;ldquo;straight&amp;rdquo; 8. A PDP 8 that&amp;rsquo;s built using diode cards, and thus, fits on a table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt;Photos&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig3.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;fig4.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;fig5.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;fig6.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;restofit&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-rest-of-the-museum-restofit&#34;&gt;The rest of the museum &lt;a href=&#34;#restofit&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the dec room, we were let into the main room of the museum. There was just too much to go over here. They had a real apple 1, a bunch of apple 2s, an apple 3, NEXT Cube, a BeBox, tons of IBMs, and way way more. And the best part, it was all hands on. We could actually use the computers on display! (not the Apple 1, the had a replica for people to play with).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt;Photos&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;fig7.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;fig8.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;fig9.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;g15&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;usagi-and-the-g15-g15&#34;&gt;Usagi and the G15 &lt;a href=&#34;#g15&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main even. David from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@UsagiElectric/videos&#34;&gt;Usagi Electric&lt;/a&gt;, was there to swap out the drum memory in a Bendix G15. He&amp;rsquo;s been restoring a G15 sent to him from the museum (yes, they have two). The drum memory in his unit was completely crashed. However, the drum in the G15 still at the museum, was fine. That&amp;rsquo;s why he was up in Maryland swapping them out. Definitely watch his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLnw98JPyObn3QSIwUz5Iv6NA1x-uGFqAa&#34;&gt;playlist on working on the G15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt;Video&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry about the sound, a lot of people were talking. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uOGCUNv8Yg8&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uOGCUNv8Yg8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt;Photos&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig10.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;fig11.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; &lt;br&gt;
A wild &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@vintagegeek&#34;&gt;Ventage Geek&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;fig12.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;fig13.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;thoughts&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts &lt;a href=&#34;#thoughts&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the museum was fantastic. I am defiantly going back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the photos I took are available on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/197704187@N04/albums/72177720312149715/with/53281603158/&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;, in their full resolution (48Mpx). So definitely check that out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20System%20Source%20Museum&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email ✉️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: System Source Museum&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bal&amp;rsquo;Mer&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Secret Guest Network - They will never know</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/secret-guest-network/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 22:52:29 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/secret-guest-network/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Imagine this, you have some people over, and they want the password to your WiFi. You trust them, but not “you can be on my network” trust them. So you give them the guest network login. They get mad and leave, and now you&amp;rsquo;re down a couple friends. But what if you could have a hidden guest network, that looks just like your main one, maybe that would let you keep some friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubiquity has rolled out support for PPSK (Private Pre Shared Keys). That let&amp;rsquo;s you have multiple networks, behind one SSID. This is handy, as having too many SSIDs can hurt performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What PPKS does, is let you automatically put a host on a VLAN, depending on what password they use. For example, let&amp;rsquo;s say we have a WiFi network called &amp;ldquo;BullsEyeWiFi&amp;rdquo;. We can set up PPSK so that anyone who uses the password &amp;ldquo;GoodPassw0rd1!&amp;rdquo;, will be put on VLAN 1. And anyone who uses the password &amp;ldquo;Playground&amp;rdquo;, will get put on VLAN 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty business example. A more home user example would be: Having a segregated guest network, on the same SSID as your main one. This way, you can put your house guests on a guest network, without them having any idea. And thus, keeping them as friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heres a good video from Cameron Gray Going over PPSK on UNiFi. And its downside (It doesn&amp;rsquo;t work on WPA3 networks (That includes 6GHz networks)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DvhU7roLviY&amp;amp;t=1228s&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DvhU7roLviY&amp;amp;t=1228s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20The%20Secret%20Guest%20Network&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📫&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: The Secret Guest Network&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Flying Home</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/flying-home/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 23:35:13 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/flying-home/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;h2 id=&#34;den-to-ind&#34;&gt;DEN to IND&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my way back home, currently on a flight from DED to IND. No problems with this one, unlike my flight out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, unlike this leg, not all is well with me. I fell pretty ill last night, and was wondering if I was going to be fit to fly the next morning. &lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into details, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t good. Thankfully, today I am just barely fit to fly. I do wish that I brought a hoodie with me, but Unfortunately, I did &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EmL3lS0-Sr8&#34;&gt;not&lt;/a&gt;. I was hoping to pick one up at the airport, but they didn&amp;rsquo;t have any in my size. I&amp;rsquo;ll check at check IND.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEN did have a really cool statue. I am a massive fan of the Apollo program (The moon landings). DEN had a statue of JOHN L.&amp;ldquo;JACK&amp;rdquo; SWIGERT, JR., the pilot of Apollo XIII. The mission that suffered an explosion of one of the oxygen tanks&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on their way to the moon. The statue is of him in his flight suite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webP&#34; alt=&#34;A statue of JOHN L.&amp;ldquo;JACK&amp;rdquo; SWIGERT, JR.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, I&amp;rsquo;m still watching plane crash documentaries. You can see a list of the ones I grabbed &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthp.me/posts/flight-update-3#list&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ind-to-bwi&#34;&gt;IND to BWI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IND was pretty simple. got in, checked where my gate was, then wen&amp;rsquo;t hunting for a hoodie. Unfortunately IND only had hoodies in small and 2XL. Great. Picked up some meds for way too much, and waited for my plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t watch anything on my flight to BWI, I just wanted to get home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon getting home, I crashed in bed for three days. All and All, I&amp;rsquo;m def going back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEN to IND was written on the plane from DEN to IND, everything else was written long after getting home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Flying%20Home&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email ✉️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Flying Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig2.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Flight Update 3 - Testing my luck</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/flight-update-3/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 23:33:55 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/flight-update-3/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;I am now on my way from RDU to DEN. &lt;br&gt;
After everyone getting off at RDU (all but 16), and a headcount was taken, we were able to move seats. I moved from the very back, to the very front. Hoping to make a speedy exit at DEN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned at the end of my last post, that my in flight entertainment is a bunch of plane crash documentaries. I downloaded 16 20 - 40 min videos by Green Dot Aviation (fantastic channel). To help make sure the person next to me doesn&amp;rsquo;t get nervous, I have the videos playing in the mini player in the corner on my mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First one I watched was about UPS flight 6, a cargo aircraft that had a cargo fire. &lt;br&gt;
The second one was Swissair flight 111, a flight that had a fire. &lt;br&gt;
The third was about BA 162, a flight that caught&amp;hellip; fire&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, not all of them are about fires, here&amp;rsquo;s all the ones I downloaded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;list&#34; /&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;19 SECONDS from Collision | Easyjet 6074.mp4
315 people TRAPPED inside a Crazy Plane! Qantas 72.mp4
747 in DANGER | The MYSTERY of the world&amp;#39;s WORST mid-air collision.mp4
CRASHING 4 minutes after takeoff | Sriwijaya Air 182.mp4
FIRE onboard!? The nightmare of Swissair 111.mp4
HOW did they forget THIS?! Malaysia 134.mp4
INFERNO over Dubai | The Horror of UPS 6.mp4
Plane SNAPS in half over the ocean | The REAL story of South African 295.mp4
Plane catches FIRE over London | BA 762.mp4
SECONDS after takeoff | Air Florida flight 90.mp4
TERRIFYING Dive | What went WRONG??.mp4
This plane RAN OUT of FUEL in the middle of the OCEAN!!.mp4
This plane RAN OUT of fuel mid-flight!.mp4
WHAT caused the WORST single air crash in history?? | Japan Air 123.mp4
WHY did this plane DIVE just before landing? | Icelandair 315.mp4
What REALLY happened Korean Flight 007??.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to post this till a fair bit after I get off the plane&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but this post was written on the plane, and will be date stamped of when I completed it, not when I post it&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. Noise canceling headphones are not only great for plane noise, but kid noise as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Flight%20Update%203&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📨&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Flight Update 3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not paying $8 just to post this.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blot let&amp;rsquo;s me do cool stuff like that.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Flight Update 2</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/flight-update-2/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 23:33:22 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/flight-update-2/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;I am on a plane, crazy I know. First I was scheduled for one flight, then I got bumped to another, but you read that (I hope). When I left off I was at gate B8 at BWI, things changed pretty quick after posting. &lt;br&gt;
I took off from (get it) the gate to use the restroom, when I got back, the flight info display was showing a different flight. What&amp;hellip; I pulled out my phone and checked my boarding pass. My gate had changed to A14, halfway across the airport&amp;hellip; I had plenty of time to get there, and I got there fine. &lt;br&gt;
I had to wait some more, as the plane at the gate hadn&amp;rsquo;t left yet, thus mine couldn&amp;rsquo;t pull in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter now, I&amp;rsquo;m in the air. and on my way to RDU in NC. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll be on to DEN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll try to post this at RDU, don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to, as I&amp;rsquo;m writing this on my Mac vs my phone. Either way, I&amp;rsquo;ll mark the post time of when I finished this. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthp.me/tagged/air-craziness&#34;&gt;Air Craziness tag&lt;/a&gt; on here for the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. My inflight entertainment is plane crash documentaries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Flight%20Update%202&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📨&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Flight Update 2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Flight Update</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/flight-update/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 23:31:34 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/flight-update/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;While waiting for my already delayed flight, I got a text saying that I had been rebooked to a new flight&amp;hellip;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Later in the day. &lt;br&gt;
I was scheduled to fly from BWI at 13:40 to ATL, then to DEN. Now I&amp;rsquo;m going from BWI at 15:25 to RDU to DEN&amp;hellip; fun. And because I was rebooked, I&amp;rsquo;ve been dumped to boarding group C out of&amp;hellip; C. It&amp;rsquo;s not all bad, while I&amp;rsquo;ll be stopping in RDU, I&amp;rsquo;m not changing planes. So I can get a better seat that way. BWI to RDU is only about 1H 5M. Hoping I don&amp;rsquo;t get any more surprises on the flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I you want to join me on this craziness, follow me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@nthp&#34;&gt;Mastodon @nthp@fosstodon.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20Flight%20Update&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email ✉️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: Flight Update&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>New Mastodon Handle</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/new-mastodon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 23:28:43 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/new-mastodon/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: This post is old and I have moved to Fosstodon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the shutting down of Crabland.social&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve migrated my account to a new server. &lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m using the same hosting provider &lt;a href=&#34;https://masto.host&#34;&gt;Masto.host&lt;/a&gt;, just can&amp;rsquo;t beat their pricing. My new server is a singer user one (not running in single user mode, because I think it looks ugly), &lt;a href=&#34;https://mstdn.nthp.me&#34;&gt;mstdn.nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try and cut down the amount of domains I own (too many), so I&amp;rsquo;m going to be tying more things to my main one (this one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all I got, if you were following my old Mastodon account, you should be automatically following my new one &lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@nthp&#34;&gt;@nthp@fosstodon.org&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m also posting this form an airport, so that&amp;rsquo;s neat&amp;hellip; my flight got delayed though&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20New%20Mastodon%20Handle&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email ✉️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: New Mastodon Handle&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig3.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Day-cation</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/the-day-cation/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 23:11:43 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/the-day-cation/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;Jump to: &lt;a href=&#34;#idea&#34;&gt;The Idea&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#planing&#34;&gt;Planing&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#trip&#34;&gt;The Trip&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Quick Links: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/197704187@N04/albums/72177720310228473&#34;&gt;Trip Photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved a good vacation, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t. But vacations take time. Time to plan. And time to take. Why not just take a day trip, you say. Why not to drive somewhere for a day, you ask. I live near DC, so a day trip is going down to DC for the whatever-ith time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;idea&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-idea-idea&#34;&gt;The Idea &lt;a href=&#34;#idea&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan started with my friend texting me. Asking if I wanted to take a trip to Atlanta. Why? He wanted to get out of something&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The idea was a day trip, fly down first thing in the morning, see some things, and fly back after lunch. Now that&amp;rsquo;s a day-cation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;planing&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planing-planing&#34;&gt;Planing &lt;a href=&#34;#planing&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why Atlanta? Well, neither me, nor my friend have been there. And the flights were cheep. Like $50 round trip cheep. There&amp;rsquo;s just one catch, we&amp;rsquo;d be flying on Spirit. More on that later. Now we just needed something to do there. Easy, they have a big aquarium, and the Coca-Cola HQ. Buying the airline tickets was pretty straight forward. The Work of Coke tickets we would just buy at the door. The aquarium tickets on the other hand, oh man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;tickets&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;buying-atlanta-tickets-from-california-in-maryland-tickets&#34;&gt;Buying Atlanta tickets, from California, In Maryland &lt;a href=&#34;#tickets&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying the aquarium tickets was an absolute pain. No matter what I did, it would just give me an error. Didn&amp;rsquo;t matter the card, time slot, or billing address, it just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Then I had an idea. I fired up a VPN to California, and bought the tickets&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t know why that worked. The problem continued. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t add the ticket to Apple Wallet&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. So I tried the same VPN to Cali trick. Boom I had my ticket. I forwarded the email to my friend so he could grab his&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;trip&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-trip-trip&#34;&gt;The Trip &lt;a href=&#34;#trip&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;flight&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-flight-flight&#34;&gt;The Flight &lt;a href=&#34;#flight&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mostly fly on South West, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know what to expect from Spirit. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect much, but damn did they fly under that. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick breakdown of the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;South West&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Spirit&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Checked Bags&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 Free&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra Charge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cary on&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Free&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra Charge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Inflight WiFi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra Charge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra Charge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Free Messaging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Soda&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Free&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra Charge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alcohol&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra Charge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra Charge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Movies&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tray Table&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lol, No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damn, that&amp;rsquo;s not great. And that&amp;rsquo;s not even the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/LPbm2tSssCQ?t=22&#34;&gt;end of it&lt;/a&gt;. The seats, oh god the seats.
I&amp;rsquo;d describe South West&amp;rsquo;s seats as, fine. They get the job done, they recline a bit, and the aren&amp;rsquo;t painful over a long flight&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Spirit&amp;rsquo;s on the other hand&amp;hellip; Our flight was 1H 50M. After about 90min, I wanted out, they were that bad. They also didn&amp;rsquo;t recline&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;atlanta&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;atlanta-atlanta&#34;&gt;Atlanta &lt;a href=&#34;#atlanta&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We landed at ATL, and took a neat, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.pinimg.com/originals/2b/ca/c1/2bcac10438ab9a950ac22ddf37b8b6e6.jpg&#34;&gt;simple train&lt;/a&gt; to the aquarium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;aqu&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-aquarium-aqu&#34;&gt;The Aquarium &lt;a href=&#34;#aqu&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aquarium was really cool, and quite &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.pinimg.com/originals/35/0f/21/350f21c24d4cb73da2aab911f7758843.jpg&#34;&gt;big&lt;/a&gt;. Not much else to say, check out my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/197704187@N04/albums/72177720310228473&#34;&gt;flicker album&lt;/a&gt; of the trip&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;coke&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;world-of-coke-coke&#34;&gt;World Of Coke &lt;a href=&#34;#coke&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a lover of Coca-Cola, I was super looking forward to World Of Coke. We started out by going into a waiting room, filled with tons of old &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/197704187@N04/53089257242/in/album-72177720310228473/&#34;&gt;coke signs&lt;/a&gt;. After being told they had a BBQ flavored soda in the tasting room. We moved into the main theater. They showed a three minute Coke ad, then in Wonka style, the theater screen moved up to reveal a entrance to the main floor&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. There was a ton of stuff. A photo op with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/197704187@N04/53089256352/in/album-72177720310228473/&#34;&gt;poler bear&lt;/a&gt;, A smelling room, that I determined  wasn&amp;rsquo;t working&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The vault&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. And the main tasting room. Filled with Coke brand sodas from around the world. They also had what I was looking for. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/197704187@N04/53090315338/in/album-72177720310228473/&#34;&gt;Fresh Coke&lt;/a&gt;. It was fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;lunch&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;lunch-lunch&#34;&gt;Lunch &lt;a href=&#34;#lunch&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After World Of Coke, we stopped off at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://discoveratlanta.com/things-to-do/sports/college-football-hall-of-fame/&#34;&gt;Chick-fil-A College Football Hall Of Fame&lt;/a&gt; for a quick bite&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Then walked around the Olympic Park for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;home&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;flight-home-home&#34;&gt;Flight Home &lt;a href=&#34;#home&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the train back to ATL, and waited for a couple hours in the TSA line. ATL was a neat airport, we took a little train like bus to our terminal&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. For some reason, Sprit wouldn&amp;rsquo;t give us boarding codes on our phones, instead telling us to see a &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.pinimg.com/originals/df/35/2f/df352f050a416b160aedf807dd02319a.jpg&#34;&gt;gate agent&lt;/a&gt;. They already had a paper boarding pass waiting for us. The flight back was exactly the same as the flight down, so just re-read that &lt;a href=&#34;#flight&#34;&gt;section&lt;/a&gt;. There and back, just in time for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;thoughts&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts &lt;a href=&#34;#thoughts&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Day-cation was fantastic, and one I highly recommend to my co-workers. As for my friend, he had to find a new excuse to not go to his thing. As we changed days to get the flight down from $80, to $50. We just couldn&amp;rsquo;t not take a $50 round trip flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/197704187@N04/albums/72177720310228473&#34;&gt;Flicker Album&lt;/a&gt; of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20The%20Day-cation&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: The Day-cation&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, I cant be at the thing, I&amp;rsquo;ll be in&amp;hellip; At&amp;hellip; lanta, sorry.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You couldn&amp;rsquo;t buy tickets at the door, you had to buy online in advance.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or load the PDF&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And told him to VPN to Cali to grab it&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also have a tray table, you know, like normal planes.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or have a tray table, wth!&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve played The Stanley Parable: Ultra Deluxe, think of when you are showed the main floor for The Stanley Parable 2&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a sense of smell.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So they claim.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The line was crazy.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad told me the hell that ATL was before the train like bus was installed.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Need to Immediately Replace</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/need-to-immediately-replace/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 22:55:39 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2023/need-to-immediately-replace/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;With the closing down of third party Reddit apps, a number of people are moving over to things like kbin. And that has me wondering, are the new users of kbin, going to try and turn it into Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something I’ve noticed over on Mastodon. When a large number a of new Mastodon users signed up, they very quickly started pushing for some new features. Those “new” features were just things that Twitter had, that Mastodon didn’t. It didn’t feel like they wanted to improve the Mastodon network. It felt like they wanted to turn it into what &lt;strong&gt;they&lt;/strong&gt; were used to, instead of getting used to Mastodon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll see if this happens with kbin and other like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20The%20Need%20to%20Immediately%20Replace&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📪&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: The Need to Immediately Replace&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>PaintBoy Advance</title>
	  <link>https://nthp.me/posts/2021/paintboy-advance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 12:10:57 -0500</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://nthp.me/posts/2021/paintboy-advance/</guid>
	  <description>
		
		&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not new to modded gameboys. I&amp;rsquo;ve put IPS screens in a DMG and an SP, and I built an &lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@Sulairris/106783968641330983&#34;&gt;all metal gameboy advance&lt;/a&gt;. Ive gotten the itch to build a custom GBA again after working on my girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s GBA, I just need an idea…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking. This is made from painting the inside of a clear shell, allowing the supports to still be seen. This isn&amp;rsquo;t mine it&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot from &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/XF_DDf9N1hc&#34;&gt;this YouTube vid&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to build the full thing yet, just see if I can make the shell myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ordered a clear replacement shell that&amp;rsquo;s been pre-modded to take an IPS display, just need to buy some spray paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many days later thanks to USPS, the shell came in the mail. It&amp;rsquo;s a clear retrosix shell and its one of the better ones I&amp;rsquo;ve seen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig2.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I needed was some spray paint, so I grabbed my super gameboy, jumped in my car and headed up to the home depot. After looking over the spray paint aisle, they didn&amp;rsquo;t really have what I was looking for, but I got something close. Oddly, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Btv1OD_CUAAICrF?format=jpg&amp;amp;name=medium&#34;&gt;my home state&lt;/a&gt; Maryalnd requires you to be at least 18 to buy spray paint. Good thing i&amp;rsquo;m 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really my first time spray painting anything, but I have watched some modding vids that go over it. After taping up the outside, cracking the garage door, I got to work. I put down one layer, then another, then another, and waited. After peeling the tape off, it came out pretty good. Some over spray on the edges, but for a first time ensnarement, it went pretty well. I&amp;rsquo;ll build something in this down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig3.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig4.webP&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me?subject=RE%3A%20PaintBoy%20Advance&#34;&gt; Reply to this post via email 📮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Webmail Users &lt;br&gt;
Address: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reply.65tu8@nthp.me&#34;&gt;reply.65tu8@nthp.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Subject: &lt;code&gt;RE: PaintBoy Advance&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>